[
  {
    "question": "In cases where a visitor travelling by air holds a valid passport and no visa is required of him, contracting states",
    "feedback": "shall not require him to obtain any other identity document from their consultates or operators prior to initiate the flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Part-FCL, a professional flight crew licence issued by a non EASA State may be rendered valid for use on aircraft registered in a EASA Member State at the discretion of the Authority of that Member State",
    "feedback": "for a period not exceeding one year, provided that the basic licence remains valid."
  },
  {
    "question": "In an instrument approach procedure, the segment in which alignment and descent for landing are made is called:",
    "feedback": "Final approach segment."
  },
  {
    "question": "The national civil aviation security programme is established by:",
    "feedback": "Each Contracting State"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the obstacle clearance in the primary area of the initial approach segment in an instrument approach procedure?",
    "feedback": "At least 300m (984 ft)."
  },
  {
    "question": "From the selection below, choose the most complete answer:\nAnnex 8 contains limitations on",
    "feedback": "limiting masses, centres of gravity positions, mass distribution and floor loading."
  },
  {
    "question": "The expression \"Expected approach time (EAT)\" is defined as follows:",
    "feedback": "The time at which ATC expects that an arriving aircraft, following a delay, will leave the holding point to complete its approach for a landing."
  },
  {
    "question": "The aircraft has made a complete stop on the apron. When leaving the aircraft, one of the passengers walks into the trailing edge of the wing and gets seriously injured:",
    "feedback": "This is an accident. The crew must follow the procedure relevant for this case"
  },
  {
    "question": "State what happens if an ILS glide path (GP) becomes inoperative during the approach:",
    "feedback": "A go-around should be initiated, or, if time permits, the approach may be continued by using the LOC signal only"
  },
  {
    "question": "The state of design shall ensure that, there exists a continuing structural integrity program to ensure the airworthiness of the aeroplane, which includes specific information concerning corrosion prevention and control, in respect of aeroplanes :",
    "feedback": "over 5.700 kg maximum certificate take-off mass"
  },
  {
    "question": "Longitudinal separation minima based on time for aircraft at the same cruising level when navigation aids permit frequent determination of position and speed will be",
    "feedback": "10 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "AIRAC is:",
    "feedback": "An acronym for a system aimed at advance notification based on common effective dates, of circumstances necessitating significant changes in operating procedures"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the figure: What does this signal from the marshaller mean?",
    "feedback": "Normal stop"
  },
  {
    "question": "The length of a clearway should not exceed:",
    "feedback": "1/2 TORA"
  },
  {
    "question": "Track separation between aircraft using the same NDB shall be applied requiring the aircraft to fly:",
    "feedback": "At least 30° separated at a distance of 15 NM or more from the facility."
  },
  {
    "question": "A NOTAM shall be originated and issued concerning the following information:\n1) Runway marking work, when the equipment used can be removed when necessary2) Runway marking work, when aircraft operations can safely be conducted on other available runways3) Routine maintenance work on aprons and taxiways which does not affect the safe movement of aircraft4) Occurrence or correction of major defects or impediments in the manoeuvring area5) Interruption of or return to operation of major components of aerodrome lighting systems6) Presence of hazards which affect air navigation7) Observations or forecasts of space weather phenomena",
    "feedback": "4, 5, 6, 7"
  },
  {
    "question": "Runway threshold lights shall be:",
    "feedback": "Fixed unidirectional lights showing green in the direction of approach to the runway."
  },
  {
    "question": "To which aircraft categories is Regulation 965/2012 applicable?",
    "feedback": "Motor-powered and non motor-powered aircraft involved in Commercial Air Transport operations (CAT) and complex and other than complex motor-powered aircraft involved in non-commercial operations"
  },
  {
    "question": "During circling-to-land ( with or without prescribed flight tracks), the maximum allowed airspeed for a Cat B aeroplane, in order to remain within the protection envelope, is:",
    "feedback": "135 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "The crew member certificate (CMC) shall be accepted by each Contracting State for identification purposes:",
    "feedback": "None of the above."
  },
  {
    "question": "A so-called \"straight-in-approach\" is considered to be acceptable for a non-precision approach if the angle between the final approach track and the runway centreline is:",
    "feedback": "30 degrees or less"
  },
  {
    "question": "Below FL 290 the Vertical Separation Minimum between controlled opposite traffic is:",
    "feedback": "1000 feet (300 m)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Load factors has the following meaning :",
    "feedback": "the ratio of a specified load to the weight of the aircraft, the former being expressed in terms of aerodynamic forces, inertia forces and ground reactions"
  },
  {
    "question": "Unaccompanied baggage carried by air shall be cleared under the procedure applicable to :",
    "feedback": "accompanied baggage or under another simplified customs procedure distinct from that normally applicable to other cargo"
  },
  {
    "question": "The part of the AIP that contains information about existing prohibited, restricted and danger areas is",
    "feedback": "ENR"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the issue of clearances by an Air Traffic Control Unit is",
    "feedback": "to prevent collision between aircraft under its control and expediting and maintaining an orderly flow of traffic"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the 1999 Montreal Convention, during which time is an airline responsible for the passenger's checked baggage?",
    "feedback": "From the baggage check-in until its off-loading"
  },
  {
    "question": "An applicant for a CPL (A) shall have completed at least the following flight time:",
    "feedback": "150 hours if following an integrated course."
  },
  {
    "question": "\"A situation wherein apprehension exists as to the safety of an aircraft and its occupants\" is the definition for:",
    "feedback": "Alert phase."
  },
  {
    "question": "A runway end safety area includes:",
    "feedback": "an area symmetrical about the extended runway centre line and adjacent to the end of the strip primarily intended to reduce the risk of damage to an aeroplane undershooting or overrrunning the runway"
  },
  {
    "question": "Following an AIRPROX incident, an Air Traffic Incident Report (ATIR) should be submitted:",
    "feedback": "to the air traffic service unit concerned"
  },
  {
    "question": "Flight information service shall be provided to all aircraft which are likely to be affected by the information and which are:",
    "feedback": "Provided with the air traffic control services or otherwise known to the relevant air traffic service units."
  },
  {
    "question": "The Standards contained in the Annexes to the Chicago Convention are to be considered:",
    "feedback": "Binding for the member States that have not notified ICAO about a national difference."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an ASHTAM used for?",
    "feedback": "Volcanic activity."
  },
  {
    "question": "How many light units are in each wing bar of a T-VASIS or AT-VASIS?",
    "feedback": "4."
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying over a mountainous region in which a search is being carried out to find the survivors of an aircraft accident. The pilot sees a ground signal in the form of an \"X\".\nThis indicates :",
    "feedback": "\"Need medical assistance\"."
  },
  {
    "question": "In accordance with the relevant Part-FCL requirements, the credit for MPA co-pilot time is:",
    "feedback": "100% of the co-pilot flight time towards the total flight time required for a higher grade of pilot licence"
  },
  {
    "question": "The inbound Magnetic Track for the holding is 052°, turns are to the right, the outbound time is 1 minute.\n\nThe appropriate entry procedure for a flight on Magnetic Track 232° with no wind is:",
    "feedback": "either offset or parallel"
  },
  {
    "question": "The objective of the Standardised European Rules of the Air (SERA) is...",
    "feedback": "to establish the common rules of the air and operational provisions regarding services and procedures in air navigation that shall be applicable to general air traffic within the scope of Regulation (EC) No 551/2004"
  },
  {
    "question": "The marking depicted in the figure is a:",
    "feedback": "runway holding position marking"
  },
  {
    "question": "Annex 8 covers the airworthiness of aircraft. Who is responsible for the administration of the Certificates of Airworthiness?",
    "feedback": "the authority of the state of registration"
  },
  {
    "question": "When an aircraft enters the traffic circuit without proper authorisation, it shall:",
    "feedback": "be permitted to land if its actions indicate that it so desires"
  },
  {
    "question": "A marshaller extends arm with wand forward of body at shoulder level; moves hand and wand to top of left shoulder and draws wand to top of right shoulder in a slicing motion across throat. What does that mean?",
    "feedback": "Cut engine(s)"
  },
  {
    "question": "A first aircraft flies under IFR, in controlled airspace, maintaining FL 150. The pilot requests a descent.\nA second aircraft flying at FL 140 on the same route requests descent and receives the clearance \"descend to FL 70, report passing FL 100\".\n\nThe aircraft at FL 150 can expect to receive a clearance for a descent to FL 140 or below when the aircraft at FL 140:",
    "feedback": "has left FL 140"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
    "feedback": "Acceptable Means of Compliance (AMC) serves as a means by which the requirements contained in the Basic Regulation, and the IR, can be met"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a take-off into IMC conditions with low ceiling the pilot should contact departure control:",
    "feedback": "When advised by Tower."
  },
  {
    "question": "A turboprop aeroplane is performing an overwater flight, which takes it further than 340 NM away from an aerodrome where an emergency landing could be performed. Normal cruising speed is 180 kt. One engine out airspeed is 155 kt.",
    "feedback": "Life jackets must be available for all occupants."
  },
  {
    "question": "The continuing airworthiness of an aircraft, according to ICAO Annex 8, shall be determined by:",
    "feedback": "The State of registry"
  },
  {
    "question": "Annex V to EU Regulation No 965/2012 (Regulation on Air Operations), Part-SPA, details ....",
    "feedback": "the operator's application, privileges, changes, and continued validity of special approvals"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Raise arm and hand, with fingers extended, horizontally in front of body, then clench fist\". This signal from a signalman to an aircraft means:",
    "feedback": "Engage brakes."
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Part-FCL, the aeroplane instructor categories recognised are:",
    "feedback": "FI(A)/TRI(A)/CRI(A)/IRI(A) and SFI authorisation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Type ratings are established for",
    "feedback": "each type of multi-pilot aeroplane (MPA)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following has had a significant effect on the role and importance of aeronautical information and flight data?",
    "feedback": "The introduction of RNAV, RNP and computer systems."
  },
  {
    "question": "The width of a runway for an aerodrome with code number 4/D should not be less than:",
    "feedback": "45 m"
  },
  {
    "question": "For a flight under VFR in airspace Class E:",
    "feedback": "two-way radio communication is not required"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft approaches an aerodrome located in controlled airspace. When a pilot reports that he has the \"field in sight\", a clearance for \"visual approach\" may be given under condition that the:",
    "feedback": "air traffic controller is able to separate this aircraft to other controlled traffic"
  },
  {
    "question": "A flight plan shall be submitted prior to departure for a controlled flight at least:",
    "feedback": "60 minutes prior to departure."
  },
  {
    "question": "When two-way radio communication is lost, a pilot should select ...... on the transponder.",
    "feedback": "Mode A, code 7600"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the climb after take-off, the change from QNH to Standard shall be made at:",
    "feedback": "the transition altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the NTZ is to:",
    "feedback": "protect aircraft that are carrying out independent parallel approaches"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the relevant Part-FCL requirements, the successful completion of multi-crew co-operation (MCC) training is one of the conditions required for:",
    "feedback": "the first type rating on multi-pilot aeroplanes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the figure: What does the signal from the marshaller mean?",
    "feedback": "Straight ahead"
  },
  {
    "question": "The general responsibility for an ATC clearance to be safe with respect to terrain clearance is with the:",
    "feedback": "pilot in command"
  },
  {
    "question": "When \"Secondary Radar\" is used, an aircraft may be identified by one of the following procedures:",
    "feedback": "Observation of compliance with an instruction to operate transponder from \"ON\" to \"STBY\" and back to \"ON\"."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the \"Aerodrome Reference Code\" the code element 2 shall identify:",
    "feedback": "The aircraft wing span."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a standard holding pattern turns are made :",
    "feedback": "to the right"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not found on the Certificate of Airworthiness?",
    "feedback": "the name and address of the owner"
  },
  {
    "question": "The primary duty provided by a radar unit is:",
    "feedback": "To provide radar separation."
  },
  {
    "question": "The longitudinal separation minima based on DME, and each aircraft  \"on track\" uses DME stations, is:",
    "feedback": "10 NM provided that the leading aircraft maintains a true airspeed of 20 kt or more faster than the succeeding aircraft."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which wake turbulence radar separation minima shall be applied between a HEAVY aircraft and a succeeding MEDIUM aircraft during the approach and departure phases of a flight.",
    "feedback": "5 nm."
  },
  {
    "question": "The minimum wake turbulence separation for landing to be applied between a MEDIUM aircraft and a HEAVY aircraft is:",
    "feedback": "2 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "At least which services have to be provided by ATS within a flight information region?",
    "feedback": "Flight information service and alerting service."
  },
  {
    "question": "The holder of a pilot licence, when acting as co-pilot at a pilot station of an aircraft certificated for operation by a single pilot but required by a Contracting State to be operated with a co-pilot, shall be entitled to be credited with:",
    "feedback": "not more than 50 % of the co-pilot flight time towards the total flight time required for a higher grade of pilot license"
  },
  {
    "question": "When an aircraft is experiencing difficulties, triggering of the alert phase is the responsibility of",
    "feedback": "air traffic control and flight information centres"
  },
  {
    "question": "Describe where a threshold should normally be located:",
    "feedback": "A threshold should normally be located at the extremity of a runway unless operational considerations justify the choice of another location"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where a parking bay is not provided at an aerodrome for the use by aircraft that have been subject to unlawful interference, what is the minimum distance that parking bay is to be from other bays?",
    "feedback": "100 m"
  },
  {
    "question": "The vertical IFR separation minimum being applied by ATC within a controlled airspace above FL 290 is:",
    "feedback": "2000 feet (600 m)."
  },
  {
    "question": "A double white cross displayed horizontally in the signal area indicates that:",
    "feedback": "the aerodrome is being used by gliders and glider flights are being performed."
  },
  {
    "question": "The objective of aviation security is to:",
    "feedback": "safeguard international civil aviation operations against acts of unlawful interference."
  },
  {
    "question": "In accordance to EU Council Directive 2003/42, the following occurrences must be reported to the competent authorities:",
    "feedback": "Aircraft deviation from ATC clearance, when a potiential for collision or near collision exists."
  },
  {
    "question": "You receive a clearance from ATC to climb to FL120, while passing altitude 2000 ft. Regarding the altimeter setting, you ......",
    "feedback": "remain on QNH until passing the transition altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft manoeuvering in an airport's circuit receives a series of red flashes from the control tower. This signifies that the aircraft must :",
    "feedback": "not land because the airport is not available for landing."
  },
  {
    "question": "What colour are apron markings?",
    "feedback": "A contrasting colour from the taxiway markings."
  },
  {
    "question": "The entry into a holding pattern shall be according to:",
    "feedback": "Magnetic heading in relation to the three entry sectors."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a precision approach category I, lighting system, the single, two and three light sources on the centre line have a length of:",
    "feedback": "300 m."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the meaning if ground-air visual signal 10?",
    "feedback": "We have found nothing but we will continue to search"
  },
  {
    "question": "A series of green flashes from aerodrome control directed towards an aircraft on ground means:",
    "feedback": "cleared to taxi"
  },
  {
    "question": "The cabin crew notify the aircraft commander that they have reasonable ground to believe that a person is about to commit an unlawful act on board the aircraft. What action should the commander take?",
    "feedback": "Impose upon that person reasonable measures, including restraining that person, to maintain good order on board"
  },
  {
    "question": "Independent parallel approaches are being conducted with vectoring to the ILS localizer course or MLS final approach track. The final vector shall be such as to enable the aircraft to intercept the ILS localiser or MLS final approach track at an angle not greater than:",
    "feedback": "30 degrees"
  },
  {
    "question": "For flights into control zones, the following meteorological conditions do not require a special VFR clearance:",
    "feedback": "Ground visibility 5 km, ceiling 1500 ft."
  },
  {
    "question": "A request for a \"clearance to maintain own separation while in VMC\" may be granted by the appropriate ATS authority. This has to be agreed by the pilot of other involved aircraft.\n\nConditions are:",
    "feedback": "airspace Class D and E, VMC, hours of daylight"
  },
  {
    "question": "To act as commander in commercial air transport on a single-pilot aeroplane, how many hours must the holder of a CPL(A) fly on a multi-engine type under IFR?",
    "feedback": "700 h & 400 h PIC"
  },
  {
    "question": "A red flare addressed to a flying aircraft means :",
    "feedback": "Notwithstanding any previous instructions, do not land for the time being."
  },
  {
    "question": "The common mark shall be selected from the series of symbols included in the radio call signs allocated :",
    "feedback": "to the International Civil Aviation Organisation by the International Telecommunication Union"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following lists all the subparts of Annex V to the EU Regulation No 965/2012 (EASA AIR OPS PART-SPA)?",
    "feedback": "General requirements, Performance-based navigation (PBN) operations, Operations with specified minimum navigation performance (MNPS), Operations in airspace with reduced vertical separation minima (RVSM), Low visibility operations (LVO), Extended range operations with two-engine aeroplanes (ETOPS), Transport of dangerous goods, Helicopter operations with night vision imaging systems, Helicopter hoist operations, Helicopter emergency medical service operations, Helicopter offshore operations"
  },
  {
    "question": "The criterion which shall be used to determine that a specific level is occupied by an aircraft shall be, (except that appropriate ATS authorities may specify a smaller criterion):",
    "feedback": "+/- 300 ft."
  },
  {
    "question": "Upon intercepting the assigned radial, the controller advises you that you are on the airway and to \"resume own navigation\". This phrase means that:",
    "feedback": "You are to assume responsibility for your own navigation."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the primary area, the obstacle clearance for the initial approach segment provides at least :",
    "feedback": "984 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "A manoeuvre in which a turn is made away from a designated track followed by a turn in the opposite direction to permit the aircraft to intercept and proceed along the reciprocal of the designated track is called a :",
    "feedback": "Procedure turn."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the correct answer with regard to definitions, according to EASA?",
    "feedback": "Implementing Rules (IR) are binding in their entirety and used to specify a high and uniform level of safety and uniform conformity and compliance"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the event of an ATC controller giving instructions which violate SERA, who is responsible for maintaining compliance with SERA?",
    "feedback": "PIC"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the relevant Part-FCL requirements, the applicant for a commercial pilot licence shall have completed in aeroplanes not less than:",
    "feedback": "10 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 5 hours may be instrument ground time"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the meaning of SAR visual signal 7 when used by survivors on the ground?",
    "feedback": "The correct answers are: Negative, Require food"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the surface of a runway is soaked but there is no standing water, the correct term is:",
    "feedback": "Wet."
  },
  {
    "question": "The period of validity for take-off slots assigned by CFMU (Central Flow Management Unit):",
    "feedback": "is 15 minutes."
  },
  {
    "question": "The correct definition for \"commercial air transport (CAT) operation\" in accordance with Regulation No 965/2012, is:",
    "feedback": "An aircraft operation to transport passengers, cargo or mail for remuneration or other valuable consideration"
  },
  {
    "question": "Subject to conditions specified by the appropriate ATS authority, a radar controller may request radar-controlled aircraft to adjust their speed when established on intermediate and final approach. This speed adjustment should not be more than:",
    "feedback": "+/- 20 kt."
  },
  {
    "question": "An AIP shall contain the following parts:",
    "feedback": "GEN, ENR, AD"
  },
  {
    "question": "The primary area of an instrument approach segment is :",
    "feedback": "A defined area symmetrically disposed about the nominal flight track in which full obstacle clearance is provided."
  },
  {
    "question": "When an aircraft is subjected to unlawful interference, the pilot-in-command shall attempt to indicate the situation to ATC by setting the transponder to Mode A, Code",
    "feedback": "7500"
  },
  {
    "question": "The accident investigation preliminary report shall be submitted to appropriate States and to the ICAO, in:",
    "feedback": "one of the working languages of ICAO"
  },
  {
    "question": "What flight are protected by the Prevention of Terrorism Act?",
    "feedback": "all flights"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the figures describes correctly the primary and secondary areas?",
    "feedback": "Figure A"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Part-MED, Class 2 medical certificate for private pilots will be valid for",
    "feedback": "60 months until age of 40, 24 months until age of 50, 12 months thereafter"
  },
  {
    "question": "If for any reasons a pilot is unable to comply with the procedures for normal conditions laid down for any particular holding pattern, he should:",
    "feedback": "advise ATC as early as possible"
  },
  {
    "question": "For independent approaches, the minimum radar separation provided until the aircraft is established inbound on the ILS localizer course and/or MLS final approach track is:",
    "feedback": "3.0 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where two aircraft are established on the same ILS localizer, what is the minimum radar separation permitted under mode 2 operations (Dependent Parallel Approaches)?",
    "feedback": "3 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where a runway has a displaced threshold and the whole of the runway is used for take-off, which of the following can be used to indicate the centre of the runway from the end to the displaced threshold?",
    "feedback": "Approach lighting (such that it does not dazzle the pilot taking-off)."
  },
  {
    "question": "A significant change in the mean surface wind direction is reported to the pilot when the mean headwind component changes by more than:",
    "feedback": "10 kt/19 km/h"
  },
  {
    "question": "Using the ground - air visual code the symbol meanning \"we have found all personnel\" is :",
    "feedback": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Annexes established by the International Civil Aviation Organisation ICAO contains ....",
    "feedback": "Standards and Recommended Practices SARPs to be adopted by the Contracting States"
  },
  {
    "question": "The rule governing flight over water for a single engined aeroplane engaged in the public transport of passengers:",
    "feedback": "limits such flight to a height sufficient to land safely if the engine fails."
  },
  {
    "question": "When letters are used for the registration mark combinations shall not be used which might be confused with the",
    "feedback": "five letter combinations used in the international code of signals"
  },
  {
    "question": "The basic ATS route designator on a chart consists of ......",
    "feedback": "1 letter of the alphabet followed by a number from 1 to 999"
  },
  {
    "question": "An ACAS RA is triggered, ordering a climb with a rate of 2000 ft/min and a few seconds later an ACAS RA is triggered ordering a descent with a rate of -2000 ft/min. What is the correct course of action?",
    "feedback": "Obey immediately to the RA and stay in safety margins of the rate of descent"
  },
  {
    "question": "A State shall provide assistance to an aircraft subjected to an act of unlawful seizure. This assistance includes :",
    "feedback": "provision of navigation aids, air traffic services and permission to land"
  },
  {
    "question": "A change from IFR to VFR will always take place only:",
    "feedback": "on the initiative of the pilot in command of an aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ACAS system is intended to assist ....",
    "feedback": "pilots by providing advice on appropriate action to avoid collision with surrounding aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "The applicant to exercise the functions of an Instrumental Flight Rating in_____ aeroplanes shall prove, according to Annex I, Personnel Licensing, his/her capability to pilot such  aircraft only by instrumental rules and an engine _________.",
    "feedback": "Multi-engine / inoperative or simulated inoperative."
  },
  {
    "question": "The longitudinal separation minima based on time between aircraft at same cruising level where navigation aids permit frequent determination of position and speed and the preceding aircraft is maintaining a true airspeed of 20 kt or more faster than the succeeding aircraft, is:",
    "feedback": "5 minutes."
  },
  {
    "question": "Aircraft A and B approach each other on converging courses in VMC at approximately the same level in a controlled airspace class D. Aircraft A is flying under IFR, aircraft B is flying under VFR.  Who has the right of way?",
    "feedback": "Aircraft B, providing it has A on its left"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft having sustained damage while on the territory of a Contracting State other than the State of Registry may fly without fare-paying passengers to an airport at which it can be restored to an airworthy condition if:",
    "feedback": "It receives permission of the State of Registry."
  },
  {
    "question": "The validity of the instrument rating aeroplane, IR(A) is:",
    "feedback": "1 year"
  },
  {
    "question": "For visual approaches, the following shall apply:\n\nA) A visual approach may only be requested when the reported ceiling is at or above the initial approach altitude/level.\nB) When so requested by a pilot, ATC is obliged to clear the aircraft for a visual approach.\nC) When cleared for a visual approach, the pilot has to maintain own separation to other aerodrome traffic.\nD) Separation has to be provided by ATC between an aircraft cleared for a visual approach and other arriving and departing aircraft.",
    "feedback": "D only."
  },
  {
    "question": "The continued validity of a Certificate of Airworthiness of an aircraft is based on:",
    "feedback": "the law of the State of Registry."
  },
  {
    "question": "According to SERA, all aircraft in flight shall display lights:",
    "feedback": "from sunset to sunrise or during any other period which may be prescribed by the appropriate authority"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of the Commission Regulation (EU) No 965/2012?",
    "feedback": "Lay down detailed rules for commercial air transport operations with aeroplanes and helicopters, including ramp inspections of aircraft of operators under the safety oversight of another State when landed at aerodromes located in the territory subject to the provisions of the treaty."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which code shall be used on Mode \"A\" to provide recognition of an aircraft subjected to unlawful interference?",
    "feedback": "Code 7500."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are regulated in Commission Regulation (EU) No 965/2012 on Air Operations, as amended?\n1) Air operator certificates2) Authorisation of high-risk commercial specialised operations3) Flight crew licensing4) Ramp inspections",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "If an accident or incident occurs, to report it, one should follow:",
    "feedback": "ICAO Annex 13"
  },
  {
    "question": "Except when a clearance is obtained from an ATC unit, flights under VFR shall not take off from an aerodrome within a Control Zone or enter a Control Zone when the",
    "feedback": "ceiling is lower than 1500 ft or the ground visibility is less than 5 km"
  },
  {
    "question": "The minimum age for obtaining a PPL is :",
    "feedback": "17 years"
  },
  {
    "question": "Aerodrome traffic is all traffic:",
    "feedback": "on the manoeuvring area and flying in the vicinity of an aerodrome"
  },
  {
    "question": "The classes of Medical certificates in EASA Part-MED are:",
    "feedback": "1 and 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "When mixing or contact does take place between passengers subjected to security control and other persons not subjected to such control after the security screening points at airports serving international civil aviation have been passed",
    "feedback": "the passengers concerned and their cabin baggage shall be re screened before boarding an aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"estimated total time\" in block 16 of a VFR flight plan is the estimated time :",
    "feedback": "required by the aircraft from take-off to arrive overhead the destination airport."
  },
  {
    "question": "When a member state allows police officers, security staff, bodyguards or other agents of foreign states to carry weapons in their territory for the protection of aircraft in flight, permission for the carriage of  weapons should be conditional upon :",
    "feedback": "Prior notification by the state of embarcation to the foreign state in which the weapons will be carried on the airport of arrival and notification of the pilot in command of a decision to permit a weapon to be carried on board his aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a contracting state renders valid a licence issued by another contracting state the validity of the authorisation",
    "feedback": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence"
  },
  {
    "question": "The definition of \"Manoeuvring Area\" is:",
    "feedback": "That part of an aerodrome to be used for take-off, landing and taxiing of aircraft, excluding apron(s)."
  },
  {
    "question": "When a RADAR operator says the following to an aircraft: \"fly heading 030\", the pilot must fly heading:",
    "feedback": "030° magnetic"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a procedure turn (45°/180°), a 45° turn away from the outbound track is performed from the start of the turn for categories C, D, E aircraft for:",
    "feedback": "1 minute 15 seconds."
  },
  {
    "question": "A person who is or will be refused admission to a state by its authorities is:",
    "feedback": "An inadmissible person"
  },
  {
    "question": "Describe why there can be no single or unique type of procedure designed that will cater for conducting a circling approach in every situation:",
    "feedback": "Each circling situation is different because of variables such as runway layout, obstacles, final approach track, wind velocity and meteorological conditions. Therefore, there can be no single procedure designed that will cater for conducting a circling approach in every situation"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a visual circling, descent below MDA/H shall not be made until:  A) Visual reference has been established and can be maintained. B) The pilot has the landing threshold in sight. C) The required obstacle clearance can be maintained and the aircraft is in a position to carry out a landing. D) A landing clearance has been received by ATC.",
    "feedback": "A, B and C"
  },
  {
    "question": "At the commencement of final approach, if the controller possesses wind information in the form of components, significant changes in the mean surface wind direction and speed shall be transmitted to aircraft. The mean tail-wind component significant change is :",
    "feedback": "2 KT"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the difference between EU regulation No. 376/2014 and EU regulation No. 996/2010:",
    "feedback": "EU regulation No. 376/2014 focuses on the reporting of occurrences and their analysis including appropriate follow-up actions, whereas EU regulation No. 996/2010 focuses more on safety investigations into accidents and serious incidents"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a VFR flight, your magnetic track is 200°. Which of the following flight levels should be used?",
    "feedback": "FL65, FL85, FL105"
  },
  {
    "question": "An applicant for a commercial pilot licence-aeroplane shall have completed not less than ........ hours of cross country flight time as pilot in command including a cross country flight totalling not less than ........  km (-NM), in the course of which full stop landings at two different aerodromes shall be made. The hours and distance refered are :",
    "feedback": "20 hours and 540 km (300NM)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Except when prescribed in procedures or made possible by agreements, aircraft under radar-control shall not be vectored closer to the boundary of controlled airspace than:",
    "feedback": "2,5 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ground - air visual signal code for use by survivors on ground indicating \"REQUIRE MEDICAL ASSISTANCE\" is :",
    "feedback": "6"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Part-FCL, an examiner's authorisation is valid for :",
    "feedback": "Not more than three years"
  },
  {
    "question": "Within Europe, certain non-scheduled commercial flights between ECAC States may be carried out without the obligation to request prior permission from the state concerned by the operator of the aircraft. This is based on which international agreement/convention?",
    "feedback": "Agreement of Paris."
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the Class of Airspace with the following conditions and services:  IFR and VFR permitted Air Traffic Control Service: all flights Separation: IFR from IFR, IFR from VFR, VFR from IFR Traffic information: in respect of other VFR flights",
    "feedback": "Airspace Class C"
  },
  {
    "question": "ATIS broadcast messages containing departure and arrival information should include cloud cover, when the clouds are :",
    "feedback": "below 1 500 m (5.000 ft) or below the highest minimum sector altitude, whichever is higher"
  },
  {
    "question": "The conventions and protocols designed to cover liability towards persons and goods on the ground, based on the international convention for rules relating to damage caused by aircraft is called convention of:",
    "feedback": "Rome 1933/1952"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following alternatives describes the complete CAT 1 ('Calvert') type of approach light system?",
    "feedback": "5 crossbars, centre line with 3, 2 and 1 lamp per light unit"
  },
  {
    "question": "You shall inform ATC as soon as your actual true airspeed and/or your time estimate for the next applicable reporting point differs from that indicated in your flight plan. This deviation is as follows:",
    "feedback": "5 %; in excess of 2 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where no barrettes are used, each centre line light position of a category I precision approach lighting system shall consist of:",
    "feedback": "A single light source in the innermost 300 m, two light sources in the central 300 m and three light sources in the outer 300 m."
  },
  {
    "question": "The speed limitation for VFR flights inside ATS airspace classified as C, when flying below 3.050 m (10.000 ft) AMSL, is :",
    "feedback": "250 KT IAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Demonstration of skill to revalidate or renew ratings, and including such oral examination as the examiner may require\" is the definition for a:",
    "feedback": "Proficiency Check"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft making a radar approach should be advised to consider executing a missed approach, if the position or identification of the aircraft is in doubt during any portion of the final approach or if the aircraft is not visible on the radar display for significant interval during the last:",
    "feedback": "2 NM."
  },
  {
    "question": "A turn executed by the aircraft during the initial approach between the end of the outbound track and the beginning of the intermediate or final approach track is a:",
    "feedback": "Base turn"
  },
  {
    "question": "If radio contact is established during interception but communication in a common language is not possible, attempts shall be made to convey instructions and essential information by using standard phrases and pronunciations, transmitting each phrase twice. The standard phrase with the meaning \"land at this aerodrome\" for use by intercepting aircraft is:",
    "feedback": "YOU LAND (YOU-LAAND)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Generally, when and where are stop bars provided?",
    "feedback": "They are positioned at all runway-holding positions for runways used when RVR is less than 350 m."
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Part-FCL, establishment of separate type rating for aeroplanes will be assessed on the basis of three criteria. One of these three criteria is that the aeroplane has :",
    "feedback": "Handling characteristics that require additional flying or simulator training"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the main objectives of ICAO is to :",
    "feedback": "develop principles and technique for international aviation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Select the correct statement(s) regarding the scope of Regulation (EU) No 965/2012 on air operations:\n1) It lays down detailed rules for commercial air transport operations with aeroplanes and helicopters2) It also applies to air operations within the scope of Regulation (EC) No 216/2008",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is not correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "ATC tells you to \"report when runway vacated\". What is your task?",
    "feedback": "Report when the aircraft is completely beyond the runway holding point"
  },
  {
    "question": "Unless otherwise published or instructed by ATC, all turns after initial entry into the holding pattern shall be made into which direction?",
    "feedback": "To the right."
  },
  {
    "question": "The convention which deals with offences against penal law, is",
    "feedback": "the convention of Tokyo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Four declared distances specified for a runway direction (TORA, TODA, ASDA, LDA) would be equal if the runway ......",
    "feedback": "is without a stopway or a clearway, and also without a displaced threshold"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the visual manoeuvring  (circling) area has been established the obstacle clearance altitude/height (OCA/H) is determined:",
    "feedback": "For each category of aircraft, and it may be different for each one of them."
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the relevant medical requirements, for the initial medical examination the validity of the medical assessment shall begin at the date the",
    "feedback": "medical examination is performed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where does the initial approach segment in an instrument approach procedure commence?",
    "feedback": "At the IAF."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following signals is a distress signal?",
    "feedback": "A parachute flare showing a red light."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the normal procedure design climb gradient for a missed approach procedure?",
    "feedback": "2.5 %"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct ?\nDuring a \"Visual Approach\" in Controlled Airspace (Class C):",
    "feedback": "ATC will apply separation  with other traffic"
  },
  {
    "question": "Independent parallel approaches may be conducted to parallel runways provided that :",
    "feedback": "the missed approach track for one approach diverges by at least 30° (degrees) from the missed approach track of the adjacent approach"
  },
  {
    "question": "A runway strip includes runway and ...",
    "feedback": "stopway to protect aircraft flying over it during take-off or landing operations"
  },
  {
    "question": "If due to an illness, a pilot is unable to act as a member of a flight crew for a period of 21 days or more, the holder of the licence shall",
    "feedback": "inform the Authority in writing when the period of 21 days has elapsed. Flight duties may only be resumed when the requirements imposed by the Authority have been met."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would be described as aerodrome traffic?",
    "feedback": "All traffic on the manoeuvring area of an aerodrome and flying in the vicinity of an aerodrome."
  },
  {
    "question": "The minimum flight visibility and distance from clouds on a VFR flight in airspace class C at 9000 ft. AMSL/2500 ft. AGL is:",
    "feedback": "5 km, distance from clouds 1500 m horizontally and 300 m vertically."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following systems describes an abbreviated precision approach path indicator:",
    "feedback": "A wing bar of 2 sharp transition multi-lamp units normally located on the left side of the runway unless it is physically impracticable to do so."
  },
  {
    "question": "When applying longitudinal separation based on distance (DME), the minimum separation between two aircraft on reciprocal tracks climbing or descending through the same flight level shall be at least:",
    "feedback": "10 nm"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Warsaw convention and the later amendments in the Montreal Convention deal with the:",
    "feedback": "operator's liability for loss and damage caused to passengers and goods"
  },
  {
    "question": "Flights under VFR, operating inside controlled airspace Class C at or above 3050 m/10000 ft AMSL have to maintain the following minima:",
    "feedback": "Flight visibility 8 km, distance from clouds: 1500 m horizontal, 300 m vertical"
  },
  {
    "question": "Any person who suffers damage on the surface caused by an aircraft in flight, or by any person or thing falling therefore, is entitled to compensation as provided by the:",
    "feedback": "Rome Convention 1933/1952"
  },
  {
    "question": "In order to avoid confusion, the identification numbers given to each prohibited area, restricted area and danger area shall not be re-used for a period of",
    "feedback": "At least one year after cancellation of the area to which they refer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding the Rome Convention, the right to damages is lost if an action is not brought within:",
    "feedback": "2 years"
  },
  {
    "question": "Three aircraft, (1), (2) and (3), arrive successively at ten minute intervals, overhead the scene of a recent aircraft accident.\n\n-aircraft (1) is unable to establish contact with the Search and Rescue Centre\n-aircraft (2) is able to contact the Search and Rescue Centre\n-aircraft (3) is a Search and Rescue helicopter\n\nThe command of the situation is the responsibility of;",
    "feedback": "(1), then by mutual consent (2) and then (3)."
  },
  {
    "question": "The privileges of the holder of an airline transport pilot licence (ATPL) shall be:",
    "feedback": "to act as pilot-in-command of aircraft engaged in commercial air transport and to exercise all the privileges of the holder of a LAPL, a PPL, and a CPL"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the correct designation for a specific location near the initial or planned geometric centre which is established for each aerodrome?",
    "feedback": "Aerodrome Reference Point"
  },
  {
    "question": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified upper limit is a",
    "feedback": "Control Zone"
  },
  {
    "question": "The closure of a runway  for a year, because of maintenance, will be published :",
    "feedback": "in NOTAM and AIP, inclusive Supplement."
  },
  {
    "question": "When a licence holder is unable to perform the flight crew functions appropriate to his licence due to illness, he shall inform the authority",
    "feedback": "the authority does not need to be informed"
  },
  {
    "question": "The privilege to land in another ICAO participating state for technical reasons is called:",
    "feedback": "the second freedom"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"VMC and own separation\" ATC clearance is used for a controlled flight to cross the level of another controlled flight when:",
    "feedback": "Requested by the pilot, during the day light and authorized by the state overflown."
  },
  {
    "question": "Describe where a radio altimeter area should be established:",
    "feedback": "A radio altimeter operating area should be established in the pre-threshold area of a precision approach runway"
  },
  {
    "question": "For the standards of Annex 8 (Airworthiness of Aircraft) to be applicable, how many engines must the aircraft have?",
    "feedback": "2 or more"
  },
  {
    "question": "Each contracting state shall establish measures to ensure that the aircraft operator is informed when passengers are obliged to travel because they have been the subject of judicial or administrative proceedings in order that appropriate security measures can be taken",
    "feedback": "the statement above question is incomplete. The pilot in command and the aircraft operator are to be informed"
  },
  {
    "question": "As part of the total flight time requirement of 1500 hours for the issue of the ATPL in accordance with the relevant Part-FCL requirements, the minimum instrument time requirements are:",
    "feedback": "75 hours of instrument time, of which not more than 30 hours may be instrument ground time"
  },
  {
    "question": "Within the Annex to the ICAO convention that specifies dimensions of aerodromes are codes for different runways. Which is the minimum width of a runway with runway code 4?",
    "feedback": "45 metres"
  },
  {
    "question": "The radar controller shall not request the pilot to adjust the speed where the aircraft has passed:",
    "feedback": "4 NM from the threshold on final approach."
  },
  {
    "question": "The protection areas associated with instrument approach procedures are determined with the assumption that turns are performed at a bank angle of:",
    "feedback": "25° or the bank angle giving a 3°/s turn rate, whichever is lower, for departure, approach or missed approach instrument procedures, as well as circling-to-land (with or without prescribed flight tracks)."
  },
  {
    "question": "According to ICAO DOC 8168, which is correct from the definitions below?",
    "feedback": "Height is the vertical distance of a level, a point or an object considered as a point, measured from a specified datum"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is meant when departure control instruct you to \"resume own navigation\" after you have been vectored to an airway?",
    "feedback": "You should maintain that airway by use of your navigation equipment."
  },
  {
    "question": "The crew has reason to believe that a passenger is about to conduct an act of illegal interference. What should the pilot-in-command do?",
    "feedback": "Take necessary actions to restrain or secure the passenger in question"
  },
  {
    "question": "When not flying over high terrain or mountainous areas and where no minimum flight altitude has been established, flights under IFR shall be flown at a level which is at least:",
    "feedback": "1000 ft above the highest obstacble located within 8 km of the estimated position of the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "For controlled traffic that shall be separated in the vicinity of an airport, separation minima may be reduced:",
    "feedback": "when the following aircraft has the preceding aircraft in sight"
  },
  {
    "question": "For the issue of an instrument rating the holder of a PPL or CPL shall have completed at least 50 hours of cross-country flight time as pilot in command of aircraft in categories acceptable to the licensing Authority. According to the relevant Part-FCL requirements, the minimum required cross country flight hours on aeroplanes are:",
    "feedback": "10 hours"
  },
  {
    "question": "The minimum services provided in a Flight Information Region (FIR) are:",
    "feedback": "Flight Information and Alerting Service"
  },
  {
    "question": "Operationally significant changes to the AIP published at a specific date are called",
    "feedback": "AIRAC"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to ICAO Annex 1, a State may issue licences:",
    "feedback": "on first-quality paper or other suitable material, including plastic cards (referred to as \"hardcopy\")"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which phase of emergency is declared if an aircraft is known or believed to be the subject of unlawful interference?",
    "feedback": "ALERFA"
  },
  {
    "question": "In flight the pilot of an aircraft observes a series of projectiles discharged from the ground at intervals of 10 seconds, each showing, on bursting, red and green lights or stars.\n\nThe meaning of this signal is:",
    "feedback": "the aircraft is flying in or is about to enter a restricted, prohibited or danger area. The aircraft is to take such remedial action as may be necessary"
  },
  {
    "question": "Detailed description of meteorological information provided at the aerodrome and an indication of which meteorological office is responsible, is in the following part of the AIP",
    "feedback": "AD"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Part-FCL, the privileges of the holder of an ATPL are, within the appropriate aircraft category, to exercise all the privileges of the holder of an ....",
    "feedback": "LAPL, PPL, and CPL, and act as PIC of aircraft engaged in commercial air transport"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Part-FCL, the privileges of a newly qualified Flight Instructor are restricted to carrying out instruction under the supervision of a FI(A), approved for this purpose. The restrictions may be removed from the rating :",
    "feedback": "On the recommendation of the supervising FI(A) after the holder of the restricted FI(A)rating has completed at least  100 hours flight instruction and , in addition, has supervised at least 25 student solo flights."
  },
  {
    "question": "An Expected Approach Time (EAT) is transmitted to an aircraft by the most expeditious means when it is expected that it has to hold",
    "feedback": "for 30 minutes or more"
  },
  {
    "question": "When letters are used for registration mark combinations shall not be used which might be confused with urgent signals for example",
    "feedback": "TTT"
  },
  {
    "question": "If runway centre line lights are installed on a runway with a length of 1800 m or more, they shall have the following colours on the last 900 m:",
    "feedback": "Alternate red and white from 900 m to 300 m and red from 300 m to the runway end."
  },
  {
    "question": "ATIS broadcast",
    "feedback": "shall not be transmitted on the voice channel of an ILS"
  },
  {
    "question": "For an aerodrome in Controlled Airspace Class C",
    "feedback": "ATC provides separation between flights under IFR and IFR/VFR.\nATC does not provide separation between flights under VFR"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Class of airspace where IFR and VFR flights are permitted, but all flights are subject to air traffic control service and are separated from each other is classified as",
    "feedback": "Class B"
  },
  {
    "question": "The acronym PAPI stands for:",
    "feedback": "Precision Approach Path Indicator."
  },
  {
    "question": "A special NOTAM series notifying a possible important change for the aircraft operation due to volcano activity, eruption or ash cloud by means of a specific format is called:",
    "feedback": "ASHTAM"
  },
  {
    "question": "A runway holding position marking shall be established on ......",
    "feedback": "a taxiway intersecting a runway and on a runway intersecting another runway if the runway is part of a standard taxi route"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the following marshalling signal mean?\n\"Arms and wands fully extended above head, moving wands outward in a \"jabbing\" motion\"",
    "feedback": "Chocks removed"
  },
  {
    "question": "With regard to the Standardised European Rules of the Air (SERA), which of the following is correct?",
    "feedback": "Visual Flight Rules (VFR) and Instrument Flight Rules (IFR) are contained in Commission Implementing Regulation (EU) No 923/2012"
  },
  {
    "question": "Security measures apply to:",
    "feedback": "airport design"
  },
  {
    "question": "Does the liability of a carrier extend to the carriage of mail and cargo as well as passengers?",
    "feedback": "Yes, but only on scheduled flights (3rd, 4th and 5th freedom flights)"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many separate segments has an instrument approach procedure?",
    "feedback": "Up to 5."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Freedom of the Air will be exercised by an airline planning a flight that will require a technical stop in a neighbouring State?",
    "feedback": "2nd freedom"
  },
  {
    "question": "A runway may be contaminated by frozen water deposits. What are the three states of frozen water reported by ATC?",
    "feedback": "Snow, ice and slush."
  },
  {
    "question": "The basic holding position shown in the figure will be used:",
    "feedback": "at an intersection of a taxiway and a non-instrument, non-precision approach or takeoff runway."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the meaning of sign 3 seen in an airfield signal square?",
    "feedback": "Glider flying in progress"
  },
  {
    "question": "In case of aircraft registered in other Contracting States, which are not engaged in schedule international services, and which are making flights across the territory of a Contracting State or stopping for non traffic purposes, such Contracting State shall accept the information contained in a flight plan as adequate advance notification. This information is to be received :",
    "feedback": "at least 2 hours in advance of arrival"
  },
  {
    "question": "For non precision approaches, the Final Approach Fix (FAF) is set at a specified distance from the threshold of the instrument runway. What is the maximum this distance can be?",
    "feedback": "19 km (10 nm)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Annex 17 to the Convention of Chicago covers:",
    "feedback": "Security"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following ICAO documents contain International Standards and Recommended Practices (SARPS)?",
    "feedback": "Annexes to the Convention on international civil aviation."
  },
  {
    "question": "The Commission Implementing Regulation (EU) No 2017/373 provides, amongst others:\n1) General requirements for the provision of air navigation services2) Specific requirements for the provision of air traffic services3) Specific requirements for the provision of meteorological services4) Specific requirements for the provision of communication, navigation or surveillance services \nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "A VFR flight when flying inside an ATS airspace classified as B has to maintain the following minima of flight visibility and distance from clouds",
    "feedback": "5 km below 3050 m (10.000 ft) AMSL 1500 m horizontally and 300 m vertically from clouds"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the transponder is unserviceable and repair is not possible at the aerodrome of departure, then:",
    "feedback": "the pilot will only be allowed to proceed to the nearest suitable airport where repair can be effected"
  },
  {
    "question": "The en-route IFR clearance expires at 0920. What does this mean ?",
    "feedback": "If the aircraft is not airborne by 0920, a new clearance has to be issued"
  },
  {
    "question": "The following applies for aircraft equipped with ACAS:\n\nA) The ACAS capability of an aircraft will normally not be known to ATC controllers.\nB) Separation minima may be reduced by ATC between aircraft equipped with ACAS.\nC) As the ACAS capability of an aircraft is known to ATC, pilots may be required to maintain their own separation in cruise.\nD) The ATS procedures to be applied to aircraft with ACAS shall be identical to those applicable to non-ACAS equipped aircraft.",
    "feedback": "A and D"
  },
  {
    "question": "An ICAO member state cannot require visa for crew members with valid crew member certificate (CMC):",
    "feedback": "when entering on duty and seeking temporary access only."
  },
  {
    "question": "An applicant for an Airline Transport Pilot Licence (ATPL) shall have completed not less than:",
    "feedback": "100 hours of night flight as pilot-in-command or as co-pilot"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two minutes separation may be used between departing aircraft if  they are to fly on the same track, when:",
    "feedback": "The preceding aircraft is 40 kt or more faster than the following aircraft."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the principal composition of a precision approach category I lighting system?",
    "feedback": "A row of lights on the extended centre line of the runway, extending over a distance of 900 m from the runway threshold and a crossbar at a distance of 300 m from the runway threshold"
  },
  {
    "question": "Changing of flight rules from IFR to VFR is possible",
    "feedback": "If the commander so requests"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is the descent gradient kept as low as possible in the intermediate approach segment?",
    "feedback": "This is the segment in which speed and configuration are adjusted."
  },
  {
    "question": "An accident is an occurrence associated with the operation of an aircraft which:",
    "feedback": "takes place between the time any person boards the aircraft with the intention of flight until such time as all such persons have disembarked where a person is fatally or seriously injured."
  },
  {
    "question": "An approaching aircraft may descend below the MSA provided:",
    "feedback": "all conditions detailed in the other three answers are fufilled"
  },
  {
    "question": "Contracting states shall not require the authorized agent or pilot-in-command to deliver to the public authorities concerned, before departure of the aircraft, more than some copies of General Declaration, Cargo Manifest and stores list. The numbers of the copies are :",
    "feedback": "3 of each"
  },
  {
    "question": "Alerting service shall be provided:",
    "feedback": "For all controlled flight, to any aircraft known or believed to be subject of unlawful interference, and in so far as practicable to all aircraft having filed a flight plan or otherwise known to the ATS."
  },
  {
    "question": "Unless otherwise prescribed by the appropriate ATS authority, the radar controller should notify the non-radar controller when an aircraft making a radar approach is approximately:",
    "feedback": "8 NM."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which convention makes acts of violence on board, destruction of aircraft in flight and destroying or damaging any air navigation facility punishable?",
    "feedback": "the Montreal Convention"
  },
  {
    "question": "Minimum sector altitudes are determined by the inbound radial in relation to the IAF. These sectors are established for a distance from the IAF of:",
    "feedback": "25 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The width of the corridor around a specified arrival route is :",
    "feedback": "± 5 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which information is not included in Instrument Approach Charts (IAC) in the AIP?",
    "feedback": "Any addition to minima when the aerodrome is used as alternate"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is information that is not given  in AIP approach and landing charts",
    "feedback": "Visibility minima"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a precision approach category I lighting system, the centre line and crossbar lights shall be:",
    "feedback": "fixed lights showing variable white"
  },
  {
    "question": "Upon receipt of the notification and a request by the state of occurence for participation, the state of design and the state of manufacture shall in the case of an accident or serious incident inform the state of occurence of the name of its representative to be present at the investigation when the aircraft :",
    "feedback": "Has a maximum mass over 2 250 kg"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pilots shall not SQUAWK IDENT unless they",
    "feedback": "are requested to do so by ATC"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pilot has observed a luminous signal at night which is requesting help. He indicates that he has received the ground signals by",
    "feedback": "switching on and off his landing lights twice or, if he is not so equipped, his navigation lights twice"
  },
  {
    "question": "Mandatory instructions signs on an aerodrome shall have the following colours:",
    "feedback": "White inscription on a red background."
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is responsible for investigation if an accident happened in a non-contracting state?",
    "feedback": "The state of registry"
  },
  {
    "question": "(CPL) Which of the statements concerning the privileges of a holder of a CPL (A) is correct?",
    "feedback": "act as PIC in commercial air transportation of any single-pilot aeroplane."
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Part-FCL, an applicant for a CPL (A) who has satisfactorily followed and completed an integrated flying training course shall have completed as a pilot of aeroplanes having a certificate of airworthiness issued or accepted by a EASA Member State at least:",
    "feedback": "150 hours of flight time"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the length of the pre-threshold centre line lighting for a standard full CAT I approach light system?",
    "feedback": "A length of at least 900 m and a distance of 150 m between the crossbars"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the \"Aerodrome Reference Code\", the \"Code Letter E\" shall identify an aircraft wing span of:",
    "feedback": "52 m up to but not including 65 m."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which ICAO annex is dedicated to facilitate the passage of passengers at the aerodromes?",
    "feedback": "Annex 9"
  },
  {
    "question": "Except in some special cases the establishement of change-over points should be limited to route segments of",
    "feedback": "60 NM or more"
  },
  {
    "question": "What lighting is required for runways to be used for take-off in an operating minimum below an RVR of approximately 400 m?",
    "feedback": "Edge lights and centerline lights"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the statements is correct :",
    "feedback": "contracting states shall accept an oral declaration of baggage from passengers and crew"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which medical certificate is required for a CPL or ATPL and by whom shall the medical checks be carried out?",
    "feedback": "Class 1 medical certificate; the first check has to be carried out by an AMC, the consecutive checks may be carried out by an AME."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following,according to ICAO Annex 13, shall be entitled to appoint an accredited representative to participate in the investigation?",
    "feedback": "any State which, on request, provides information, facilities or experts to the State conducting the investigation"
  },
  {
    "question": "The expression \"radar contact\" in RT phraseology means:",
    "feedback": "the radar identity of the aircraft has been established"
  },
  {
    "question": "An information issued by a meteorological watch office concerning the occurence or expected occurence of specified en-route weather phenomena which may affect the safety of low-level aircraft operations and which was not already included in the forecast issued for low level flights in the flight information region concerned or sub-area thereof is",
    "feedback": "An AIRMET information"
  },
  {
    "question": "High intensity obstacle lights are:",
    "feedback": "flashing white"
  },
  {
    "question": "You are on an NDB approach to runway 11, using QFE. Which of the following references are you going to use if the following values are given?\nAerodrome elevation: 42 ftElevation of runway 29: 38 ftElevation of runway 11: 30 ft",
    "feedback": "30 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "The part of the AIP that gives detailed information about refuelling facilities and the fuel grades available is",
    "feedback": "AD"
  },
  {
    "question": "EASA certification specifications are....",
    "feedback": "non-binding technical standards, adopted by EASA, to meet the essential requirements of the basic regulation"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a holding pattern, turns are to be made:",
    "feedback": "At a bank angle of 25° or at a rate of 3° per second, whichever requires the lesser bank."
  },
  {
    "question": "Information about SIGMET can be found in part",
    "feedback": "GEN"
  },
  {
    "question": "A circling approach is the extension of an instrument approach procedure",
    "feedback": "allowing visual circling prior to landing"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do you do, if feasible, after receiving a distress message from an aircraft near your position?",
    "feedback": "Proceed to the location of occurrence and stay there and coordinate the operation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Temporary AIP changes of \"long duration\" published in AIP supplements are changes that last for at least:",
    "feedback": "three months"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the relevant FCL requirements, the successful completion of multi-crew cooperation (MCC) training is one of the conditions required for:",
    "feedback": "the first type rating on multi-pilot aeroplanes"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to ICAO Annex 8, a Certificate of Airworthiness shall be renewed or shall remain valid, provided that the State of Registry shall require that the continuing airworthiness of the aircraft has been determined by periodical inspection at appropriate intervals having regard to lapse of time and type of service or alternatively....",
    "feedback": "by means of a system of inspection, approved by the State, that will produce at least an equivalent result"
  },
  {
    "question": "Except when necessary for take-off or landing, a VFR flight over congested areas of cities, towns or settlements or over an open-air assembly of persons shall not be flown at a height less than",
    "feedback": "300 m. above the highest obstacle within a radius of 600 m from the aircraft."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following flight levels are correct cruising levels for a VFR flight with a magnetic track of 200 degrees?",
    "feedback": "FL 65, FL 85, FL 105"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the relevant Part-FCL requirements, the validity of an instrument rating aeroplane IR(A) is:",
    "feedback": "1 year"
  },
  {
    "question": "For the construction of precision approaches, which is the operationally preferred glide path angle?",
    "feedback": "3°"
  },
  {
    "question": "The request for a speed adjustment that a pilot may expect on intermediate and/or final approach should not exceed plus/minus:",
    "feedback": "20 kt IAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "A checklist of AIP supplements currently in force shall be issued at intervals of :",
    "feedback": "Not more than one month"
  },
  {
    "question": "In relation to the three entry sectors, the entry into the holding pattern shall be according to:",
    "feedback": "Heading."
  },
  {
    "question": "Aircraft flying along the same track may be separated by DME-distances from the same DME and it is confirmed that the aircraft have passed each other. Specify the shortest difference in DME-distance to make it possible for one aircraft to climb or descend",
    "feedback": "10 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to ICAO Annex 13, what mass does ICAO mean when referring to the maximum mass in an accident investigation?",
    "feedback": "Maximum certificated take-of mass"
  },
  {
    "question": "After landing, while taxiing the landing gear sinks into a hole. No person gets injured, but the aircraft sustains structural failure, obliging the crew to delay the departure.",
    "feedback": "This is an accident and the crew must follow the procedure relevant to this case."
  },
  {
    "question": "An integrated aeronautical information package consists of the following elements",
    "feedback": "AIP, including amendment service; supplements to AIP; NOTAM and pre-flight information bulletin (PIB); AIC; checklists and summaries"
  },
  {
    "question": "For a full Calvert CAT I approach lighting system, how many bars are required and what is the configuration of the centerline?",
    "feedback": "5 bar and distance-coded centerline increasing from the threshold"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a threshold is displaced, the colour of the lights in approach direction between the beginning of the runway and the displaced threshold are:",
    "feedback": "red"
  },
  {
    "question": "Each contracting state shall designate an appropriate authority within its administration to be responsible for the development, implementation and maintenance of the national civil aviation security programme. The said appropriate authority :",
    "feedback": "Shall be specified to ICAO"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a transponder code is assigned to an aircraft and two way radio communication is lost without the possibility of reestablishment, the transponder setting to indicate COM failure is",
    "feedback": "Mode A code 7600"
  },
  {
    "question": "Minimum sector altitudes published on approach charts provide at least the following obstacle clearance:",
    "feedback": "300 m within 25 nm of the homing facility associated with the approach procedure for that aerodrome."
  },
  {
    "question": "The procedure to be followed after having experienced a two way communication failure during a flight under IFR in VMC is:",
    "feedback": "continue to fly in VMC, land at the nearest suitable aerodrome and report its arrival by most expeditious means to the appropriate ATS unit"
  },
  {
    "question": "An intercepting aircraft communicates to the intercepted aircraft \"YOU MAY PROCEED\"",
    "feedback": "with an abrupt break-away manoeuvre from the intercepted aircraft consisting of a climbing turn of 90 degrees or more without crossing the line of flight of the intercepted aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a VFR flight in airspace class B, what is the minimum distance from clouds?",
    "feedback": "300 m vertically, 1500 m horizontally."
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying under Instrument Flight Rules in an area where the visibility is unlimited and the sky is clear (free of clouds), when it totally loses radiocommunications. The procedure to be followed is:",
    "feedback": "land on the closest appropriate aerodrome, then advise Air Traffic Services of landing"
  },
  {
    "question": "The validity period of a type rating is",
    "feedback": "one year"
  },
  {
    "question": "Turning departures provide track guidance within :",
    "feedback": "10 Km"
  },
  {
    "question": "The applicant for a commercial pilot licence aeroplane shall have completed in aeroplanes not less than:",
    "feedback": "200 hours of flight time or 150 hours if completed during a course of approved training as a pilot of aeroplanes"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the ground visibility is reported 1000 m, can a special VFR flight take off from an aerodrome in a control zone?",
    "feedback": "No."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name for a taxiway connected to a runway at an acute angle designed to allow aeroplanes to turn off at higher speeds than are achieved on other exits thereby minimising runway occupancy time?",
    "feedback": "Rapid exit taxiway."
  },
  {
    "question": "In general, which is the main factor that dictates the design of an instrument departure procedure?",
    "feedback": "The terrain surrounding the airport."
  },
  {
    "question": "The Second Freedom of the air as defined in the International Air Services Transit Agreement is the right for non-scheduled flights to:",
    "feedback": "land for a technical stop in another State"
  },
  {
    "question": "An ATS airspace where IFR and VFR flights are permitted, all flights are subject to air traffic control service and are separated from each other is classified as",
    "feedback": "Airspace B"
  },
  {
    "question": "The minimum radar separation to be provided to aircraft established on the localizer course shall be:",
    "feedback": "3.0 NM between aircraft on the same localizer course."
  },
  {
    "question": "Describe how far a radio altimeter operating area should extend laterally and longitudinally:",
    "feedback": "Laterally: A radio altimeter operating area should extend laterally, on each side of the extended centre line of the runway, to a distance of 60 m, except that, when special circumstances so warrant, the distance may be reduced to no less than 30 m if an aeronautical study indicated that such reduction would not affect the safety of operations of aircraft.Longitudinally: A radio altimeter operating area should extend before the threshold for a distance of at least 300 m."
  },
  {
    "question": "The holder of a licence with a night flying qualification that does not include a valid IR (A) and not operating under EASA AIR OPS shall not act as a PIC of aeroplane carrying passengers at night unless",
    "feedback": "during the previous 90 days, at least one landing has been carried out at night."
  },
  {
    "question": "Sign 4 is a:",
    "feedback": "information sign"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to international agreements wind direction shall be adjusted to the local variation and given in degrees magnetic:",
    "feedback": "Before take-off and landing"
  },
  {
    "question": "Appropriate actions of crew members can minimize the consequences of acts of unlawful interference, thererefore the operator:",
    "feedback": "establishes and maintains an approved security training programme"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the second freedom of the air permit?",
    "feedback": "to land for technical purposes (non commercial) in the territory of another state"
  },
  {
    "question": "Low intensity obstacle lights on vehicles other than those associated with emergency or security shall be:",
    "feedback": "flashing yellow"
  },
  {
    "question": "A horizontal white dumb-bell with a black bar placed perpendicular to the shaft across each circular portion placed in the signal area indicates that:",
    "feedback": "aircraft are required to land and take off on runways only, but other manoeuvres do not need to be confined to runways or taxiways"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the first character of the registration mark is a letter:",
    "feedback": "it shall be preceded by a hyphen"
  },
  {
    "question": "In airspace Class E below 3050 m/10000 ft AMSL the maximum speed for flights under IFR is",
    "feedback": "250 kt IAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "A four-engine aeroplane is about to take-off from an airport where poor weather conditions are prevailing. The closest accessible aerodrome is three flying hours away. The take-off minima to be observed at departure airfield are:",
    "feedback": "ceiling greater or equal to DH/MDH, and VH (horizontal visibility) greater or equal to VH required for landing, with an available instrument approach procedure"
  },
  {
    "question": "Unless otherwise prescribed by the appropriate ATS authority, the horizontal radar separation minimum shall be:",
    "feedback": "5.0 NM."
  },
  {
    "question": "The final authority as to the disposition of an aircraft lies with the:",
    "feedback": "Pilot-in-command"
  },
  {
    "question": "For VFR flights, continuous two way radio communication with ATS is required in the following airspace classes.",
    "feedback": "B, C, D."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which letter is used in a flight plan to indicate that the flight commences in accordance with VFR and subsequently changes to IFR?",
    "feedback": "Z"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Single Pilot, Single Engine Class Rating is valid for:",
    "feedback": "Two years"
  },
  {
    "question": "When using the PAPI and the position of the aircraft is well above the approach slope, the pilot sees the following lights:",
    "feedback": "All the four units are steady white"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ATIS broadcast message should, whenever practicable, not exceed",
    "feedback": "30 seconds"
  },
  {
    "question": "The publication containing information on Rules of the Air, Air Traffic Services and Air Navigation Procedures, distributed in advance to become effective at a specific date is called",
    "feedback": "AIRAC"
  },
  {
    "question": "A checklist of NOTAM currently in force shall be issued at the AFTN at intervals of :",
    "feedback": "Not more than one month"
  },
  {
    "question": "When aerodrome signs are situated close to or next to a runway or taxiway, certain requirements regarding their height have to be observed. This is in order to provide clearance for:",
    "feedback": "Aircraft propellers or engine pods"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is in the climb when the pilots receive an ACAS Resolution Advisory to descend. They must follow the RA immediately because the ACAS system anticipates ....",
    "feedback": "their response will be correct and timely"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where an operational advantage can be obtained, an ILS procedure may include a dead reckoning segment from a fix to the localizer. The DR track will:",
    "feedback": "Intersect the localizer at 45° and will not be more 10 NM in length."
  },
  {
    "question": "The Air Navigation Commission is composed of:",
    "feedback": "19 members appointed by the ICAO Council"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the Class of Airspace with the following conditions and services:\n\nIFR and VFR permitted\nAir Traffic Control Service: none\nSeparation: not provided\nInformation: Flight Information Service if requested",
    "feedback": "Airspace G"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ICAO Annex dealing with the registration and marking of aircraft is:",
    "feedback": "Annex 7"
  },
  {
    "question": "A rescue coordination centre shall immediately alert search and rescue units and initiate any necessry action upon occurrence of the",
    "feedback": "Alert phase"
  },
  {
    "question": "Above FL 290 the Vertical Separation Minimum (VSM) shall be:",
    "feedback": "2000 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Containers or packages containing survival equipment for dropping should have the general nature of the content indicated by a colour code.  The colour of droppable containers and streamers for food and water is:",
    "feedback": "Blue"
  },
  {
    "question": "Under certain circumstances a medical examination may be deferred at the discretion of the licensing Authority, provided that such deferment shall only be made as an exception and shall not exceed:",
    "feedback": "a single period of six months in the case of a flight crew member of an aircraft engaged in non-commercial operations"
  },
  {
    "question": "The convention signed by the states and moved by a desire to ensure adequate compensation for persons who suffer damage caused on the surface by foreign aircraft is:",
    "feedback": "the Rome Convention 1933/1952"
  },
  {
    "question": "In accordance to Part-FCL, class ratings are established for Single Pilot Single Engine Aeroplanes not requiring a Type Rating. These can include:",
    "feedback": "Touring Motor Glider/TMG"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a procedure turn (45°/180°), a 45° turn away from the outbound track is performed from the start of turn for categories A and B aircraft for:",
    "feedback": "1 minute."
  },
  {
    "question": "When an aircraft subjected to an act of unlawful interference must depart from its assigned track or its assigned cruising level without being able to make radiotelephony contact with ATS, the pilot-in-command should, whenever possible:",
    "feedback": "attempt to broadcast warnings on the frequency in use, or on an emergency frequency"
  },
  {
    "question": "Aircraft in which wake turbulence category shall include their category immediately after the call sign in the initial radiotelephony contact with the aerodrome control tower or the approach control office prior to departure or arrival.",
    "feedback": "Heavy aircraft."
  },
  {
    "question": "On IFR flights, who is responsible for the prevention of collision with terrain?\n\nA) The Pilot.\nB) ATC, when IFR flights are vectored by radar.\nC) The Pilot and ATC in close co-operation.\nD) ATC, if the respective unit is equipped with SSR.",
    "feedback": "Combination of A and B."
  },
  {
    "question": "The right to damages is lost if an action is not brought within 2 years, this time starts from:",
    "feedback": "the date of arrival at the destination, or from the date on which the aircraft ought to have arrived, or from the date on which the carriage ceased"
  },
  {
    "question": "When letters are used for registration mark combinations shall not be used which might be confused with urgent signals for example",
    "feedback": "PAN"
  },
  {
    "question": "An OCA is referenced to:",
    "feedback": "Mean Sea Level"
  },
  {
    "question": "A change from IFR to VFR is initiated by:",
    "feedback": "the pilot in command"
  },
  {
    "question": "Air Traffic Service unit means:",
    "feedback": "Air Traffic Control units, Flight Information Centers or Air Services reporting offices."
  },
  {
    "question": "A red pyrotechnic discharged from aerodrome control to an aircraft in flight means",
    "feedback": "Notwithstanding any previous instructions, do not land for the time being"
  },
  {
    "question": "When desinsecting is required by a Contracting State as a public health measure, the desinsecting is made when the aircraft is suitably equipped by means of an automatic dispersal or vapour while the aircraft is flying, but as far in advance as possible and:",
    "feedback": "At least 30 minute prior to land."
  },
  {
    "question": "The Convention describing the authority of the pilot-in-command in case of offences and certain acts committed on board aircraft, is:",
    "feedback": "the Convention of Tokyo"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft in climb or descent is considered to have crossed a level when the SSR mode C derived level information indicates that it has passed this level in the required direction by:",
    "feedback": "More than 300 ft."
  },
  {
    "question": "What colour is taxiway edge lighting?",
    "feedback": "Blue"
  },
  {
    "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional Runway End Lights shall be:",
    "feedback": "red"
  },
  {
    "question": "The international convention defining rules relative to the responsibilities of international air carriers for the carriage of passengers, baggage and freight is the :",
    "feedback": "Warsaw Convention."
  },
  {
    "question": "When following an instrument approach, visual contact with the runway is lost on the downwind leg, the procedure to be followed is as follows:",
    "feedback": "Make an initial climbing turn towards the landing runway and initiate the respective missed approach procedure"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the content of section 2 of Air-Report (AIREP)?",
    "feedback": "Estimated time of arrival (ETA), endurance."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where unaccompanied baggage is to be carried on board an aircraft:",
    "feedback": "additional security measures need to be applied"
  },
  {
    "question": "A series of red flashes from aerodrome control directed towards an aircraft in flight means",
    "feedback": "aerodrome unsafe, do not land"
  },
  {
    "question": "For a category I precision approach, the decision height cannot be lower than :",
    "feedback": "200 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "The VMC minima for VFR flights in class B airspace, above 3050 m (10000 ft) are:",
    "feedback": "8 km visibility, 1500 m horizontal and 1000 ft vertical distance from clouds ;"
  },
  {
    "question": "Radar controlled aircraft on intermediate or final approach may be requested to make minor speed adjustments by ATC. These adjustments shall never be more than :",
    "feedback": "20 knots and not within 4 NM of threshold"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Annex 7, the registration mark shall be letters, numbers or a combination of letters and numbers and shall be that assigned by :",
    "feedback": "the state of registry or common mark registering authority"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where does the initial phase of a missed approach procedure end?",
    "feedback": "At the point where the climb is established."
  },
  {
    "question": "ICAO Annex 7 contains...",
    "feedback": "standards but no recommended practices"
  },
  {
    "question": "The movement area of an aerodrome, the adjacent lands and buildings or portions thereof with controlled access is called:",
    "feedback": "Airside"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the correct location of the RESA?",
    "feedback": "At the end of a runway strip"
  },
  {
    "question": "According with the \"Aerodrome Reference Code\" the \"Code number 4\" shall identify an aircraft reference field length of:",
    "feedback": "1 800 m and over."
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the functions ensured by a radar control unit for the provision of approach control service is:",
    "feedback": "To conduct precision radar approach (PAR)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Any contracting state may denounce the Convention of Tokyo by notification addressed",
    "feedback": "International Civil Aviation Organisation"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the Chicago Convention, aircraft of contracting states shall have the right to make flights into or in transit non-stop across the territory of other contracting states and to make stops for non-traffic purposes without the necessity of obtaining prior permission. This applies to the following flights:",
    "feedback": "To aircraft not engaged in scheduled international air services."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are flying VFR on a compass heading of 175°. The deviation is 4°E, variation 1°W. The correct flight level to be used is:",
    "feedback": "FL75"
  },
  {
    "question": "When radar identification of an aircraft has been achieved, the radar controller shall:",
    "feedback": "inform the pilot"
  },
  {
    "question": "Describe the location of NO ENTRY signs:",
    "feedback": "Immediately before the prohibited area on both sides of the taxiway"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pilot requests to pass through the level of another aircraft on the same track. He has to expect instructions:",
    "feedback": "allowing minimum longitudinal separation based on time"
  },
  {
    "question": "An ATS airspace where IFR and VFR flights are permitted and all flights are subject to air traffic control service. IFR flights are separated from other IFR flights and receive traffic information in respect of VFR flights. VFR flights receive traffic information in respect of all other flights, is classified as",
    "feedback": "Airspace D"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Traffic to which the provision of ATC is applicable, but which, in relation to a particular controlled flight, is not separated therefrom by the minima set forth\" is called:",
    "feedback": "Essential traffic."
  },
  {
    "question": "When the first character of the registration mark is a letter:",
    "feedback": "It shall be preceded by a hyphen"
  },
  {
    "question": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth is a(n)",
    "feedback": "Control Area"
  },
  {
    "question": "As part of the total flight time requirement of 1500 hours for the issue of the ATPL in accordance with the relevant Part-FCL requirements, the minimum requirements for night flight time are:",
    "feedback": "100 hours of night flight as pilot in command or as co-pilot"
  },
  {
    "question": "Alert phase is defined as follows:",
    "feedback": "apprehension exists as to the safety of an aircraft and its occupants"
  },
  {
    "question": "Runway-lead-in lighting shall consist of:",
    "feedback": "groups of at least three white lights flashing in sequence towards the runway"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Cabotage?",
    "feedback": "limitation of domestic scheduled air services to a national carrier"
  },
  {
    "question": "At what moment during the approach should the reported airfield altimeter setting be set?",
    "feedback": "When passing the transition level"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dependent parallel approaches may be conducted to parallel runways provided that the missed approach track for one approach diverges by :",
    "feedback": "at least 30° (degrees) from the missed approach track of the adjacent approach"
  },
  {
    "question": "A turning departure is one in which the initial departure track deviates from the alignment of the extended runway centre line by more than:",
    "feedback": "15°"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to ICAO Annex 2, which phrase would be used by an intercepted aircraft for the meaning \"position unknown\"?",
    "feedback": "Am lost"
  },
  {
    "question": "Under which conditions may an aircraft on a straight-in-VOR approach continue its descend below the OCA?",
    "feedback": "When the aircraft is in visual contact with the ground and with the runway lights in sight"
  },
  {
    "question": "Under Radar control, a pilot receives missed approach instructions from Radar when the tower has not issued the clearance to land by the time the aircraft reaches a distance from touch down of:",
    "feedback": "2 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The privilege for an airplane registered in one state and enroute to or from that state, to take on passengers, mail and cargo in a second state and put them down in a third state is called:",
    "feedback": "5th freedom rights"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following registration marks would not be permitted?",
    "feedback": "SY-PAN"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the figure. The marshaller moves the hand up closed in a fist and open the palm after ensuring eye contact with you. What does that mean?",
    "feedback": "You can safely release the brakes"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Vertical Separation Minima (VSM) between opposite aircraft flying under IFR, within controlled airspace below FL 290 is:",
    "feedback": "1000 feet (300 m)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where shall flight level zero be located?",
    "feedback": "At the atmospheric pressure level of 1013.25 hPa"
  },
  {
    "question": "Based on operational considerations, a margin may be added to the OCA of a non-precision approach. The result is then called:",
    "feedback": "MDA"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many NM shall a Control Zone extend at least from a reference point of the aerodrome or aerodromes into the direction from which approaches may be made?",
    "feedback": "5 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Taxiway centre line lights other than an exit taxiway are fixed lights showing:",
    "feedback": "green"
  },
  {
    "question": "A complete missed approach procedure consists of the following phases:",
    "feedback": "initial, intermediate and final"
  },
  {
    "question": "When on a RNP 1 route is indicated B235 Y, means that all turns shall be made within the allowable RNP tolerance of a tangential arc between the straight leg segments defined with a radius of :",
    "feedback": "22.5 NM between 30° and 90° at and above FL200"
  },
  {
    "question": "When an aircraft is subjected to unlawful interference, the pilot in command shall indicate the situation by setting the transponder to Mode A, Code:",
    "feedback": "7500"
  },
  {
    "question": "You are flying on a VFR flight in VMC in a controlled airspace. Suddenly, you realize you are unable to maintain VMC under the current conditions. What are your actions according to ICAO Annex 2?",
    "feedback": "Request a Special VFR clearance if flying in a Control Zone (CTR)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following statements applies to the general organisation and objectives of the IATA?\n\nThe IATA is:",
    "feedback": "An international trade body which represents, leads and serves airline business in general"
  },
  {
    "question": "Over high terrain or mountainous areas and where no minimum flight altitude has been established, flights under IFR shall be flown at a level which is at least:",
    "feedback": "2000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 8 km of the estimated position of the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "While on IFR flight, a pilot has an emergency which causes a deviation from an ATC clearance. What action must be taken?",
    "feedback": "The appropriate ATC unit shall be notified of the action taken as soon as circumstances permit"
  },
  {
    "question": "If an arriving aircraft is making a straight in approach a departing aircraft may take off in any direction",
    "feedback": "until five minutes before the arriving aircraft is estimated to be over the instrument runway"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to ICAO DOC 4444, which of the below are items of an ATC clearance that shall always be read back?\n1) Altimeter settings2) ATC route clearances3) Taxi clearance4) Correct time5) Runway in use6) Speed instructions7) Wind speed and direction",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 5, 6"
  },
  {
    "question": "There are conditions for the establishment of a type rating. Amongst other conditions type ratings are established for",
    "feedback": "for any type of aircraft whenever considered necessary by the authority"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Visual Manoeuvring (Circling) Area may be sectored to exclude a prominent obstacle. Under what circumstances is this permitted?",
    "feedback": "The obstacle is outside the final approach or missed approach areas."
  },
  {
    "question": "You fly a track of 010°(T) and 355°(M). What is the lowest flight level you can fly above FL280 in non-RVSM airspace?",
    "feedback": "FL310"
  },
  {
    "question": "Whenever a distress signal and/or message or equivalent transmission is intercepted by the PIC of an aircraft, he shall:",
    "feedback": "a and c."
  },
  {
    "question": "A MEDIUM wake turbulence aircraft is following a HEAVY category aircraft on a radar vectored approach to land. What is the radar separation minimum to be applied?",
    "feedback": "Normal radar separation of 5 nm."
  },
  {
    "question": "When two aircraft are approaching head-on or approximately so and there is a danger of collision, each aircraft shall:",
    "feedback": "alter its heading to the right"
  },
  {
    "question": "The aircraft is using QFE on an NDB approach. The pilot is informed by ATC that the aircraft's vertical position will be expressed as height above the runway threshold elevation, when .....",
    "feedback": "the threshold is 7 ft or more below the aerodrome elevation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct concerning the flight crew compartment door?",
    "feedback": "it must be capable of being locked"
  },
  {
    "question": "Flying an Instrument Departure Procedure pilots are expected to:",
    "feedback": "correct the track for known wind to remain within the protected airspace"
  },
  {
    "question": "You are the first one who arrives at an area where an accident has happened. Before any search and rescue services arrive ......",
    "feedback": "you take charge of on-scene activities of all other aircraft subsequently arriving"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pilot of an aircaft losing two-way communications shall set the transponder to Mode A Code:",
    "feedback": "7600."
  },
  {
    "question": "Containers or packages containing survival equipment for dropping should have the general nature of the content indicated by a colour code.\n\nThe colour for blankets and protective clothing is:",
    "feedback": "Yellow"
  },
  {
    "question": "The minimum wake turbulence separation to be applied between a LIGHT or MEDIUM aircraft, taking off behind a HEAVY aircraft using the same runway is",
    "feedback": "2 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does a white line drawn across a runway indicate?",
    "feedback": "A displaced threshold."
  },
  {
    "question": "If an applicant wishes to obtain an aeroplane night rating, he/she shall have completed....",
    "feedback": "at least 5 hours of flight time in the appropriate aircraft category at night and 5 solo take-offs and 5 solo full-stop landings"
  },
  {
    "question": "Longitudinal separation minima based on time for aircraft at the same cruising level when navigation aids permit frequent determination of position and speed provided that the preceding aircraft is maintaining a true air speed of 20 Kt or more faster than the succeeding aircraft will be",
    "feedback": "5 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following defines a visual approach?",
    "feedback": "When an instrument approach is not completed and visual reference to terrain is subsequently maintained."
  },
  {
    "question": "Within controlled airspace, IFR cruising levels shall be given as flight level (FL)",
    "feedback": "above the transition level"
  },
  {
    "question": "5th freedom of the air is:",
    "feedback": "the right to carry revenue traffic between any points of landing on flights between 3 or more treaty partner nations (B to C to D)"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Crew Member Certificate (CMC):",
    "feedback": "needs not be accompanied by a passport or visa but does not replace logbook or pilot's license."
  },
  {
    "question": "The minimum radar separation provided between aircraft established on the same localizer course, disregarding additional longitudinal separation as required for wake turbulence, shall be:",
    "feedback": "2.5 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Whenever a distress transmission is intercepted by a pilot-in-command of an aicraft, the pilot shall, if feasible ....",
    "feedback": "acknowledge the distress transmission and record the position of the aircraft in distress if given"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to ICAO DOC 8168, the abbreviation \"CAT\" means:",
    "feedback": "Category"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is making an entry into the CLE VOR standard holding pattern and the wind is calm. The inbound track is 270° and the aircraft is approaching on a track of 050°. The entry will be ......",
    "feedback": "offset"
  },
  {
    "question": "The maximum IAS in airspace Class E is:",
    "feedback": "for IFR and VFR, 250 kt up to FL 100/10000 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "If no ICAO identifier has been attributed to an alternate airport (box 16) of a flight plan form...",
    "feedback": "write ZZZZ in box 16 and indicate in box 18 (additional information) ALTN/followed by the name of theairport."
  },
  {
    "question": "At or above FL 290, in RVSM airspace, the Vertical Separation Minimum for controlled traffic flying in the same direction is",
    "feedback": "2000 feet (600 m)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Longitudinal separation minima based on time for aircraft at the same cruising level when navigation aids permit frequent determination of position and speed provided that the preceding aircraft is maintaining a true air speed of 40 Kt or more faster than the succeeding aircraft will be",
    "feedback": "3 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "(IR) An ETA for an IFR flight refers to the following:",
    "feedback": "IAF."
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the general rules of Standardised European Rules of the Air (SERA), which minimum height is appropriate when flying over congested areas of cities, towns or settlements?",
    "feedback": "A height which, in the event of an emergency, will permit a landing to be made without undue hazard to persons on the surface"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a PIC observes that either another aircraft or a surface craft is in distress he shall, unless he is unable, or in the circumstances of the case considers it unreasonable or unnecessary:",
    "feedback": "All of the above."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the meaning of the ground-air visual signal 8?",
    "feedback": "Proceeding in this direction"
  },
  {
    "question": "The holder of an ATPL(A) is given the same privileges as:",
    "feedback": "PPL(A), LAPL(A), and CPL(A)"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the obligation of a State in the event of non-compliance with an International Standard?",
    "feedback": "The State has to notify the Council of ICAO and publish such differences in the national AIP."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the expression for a dangerous approximation of two aircraft in the air?",
    "feedback": "AIRPROX"
  },
  {
    "question": "Runway edge lights shall consist of at least:",
    "feedback": "fixed lights showing variable white"
  },
  {
    "question": "For a circling it is permissible to disregard a prominent obstacle in a particular sector outside the final approach and missed approach area.\n\nWhen this option is exercised, the published procedure:",
    "feedback": "prohibits circling within the total sector in which the obstacle exists"
  },
  {
    "question": "A State shall take adequate measures for the safety of passengers and crew of an aircraft which is subjected to an act of unlawful interference,",
    "feedback": "until their journey can be continued"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following correctly defines Special VFR?",
    "feedback": "A flight cleared by ATC to operate within a CTR in conditions below VMC."
  },
  {
    "question": "A Special Air Report shall be made:",
    "feedback": "when experiencing severe icing or severe turbulence"
  },
  {
    "question": "The minimum obstacle clearance in the primary area of the initial approach segment for an instrument approach procedure is at least:",
    "feedback": "300 m (984 ft)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The lower limit of a Control Area is established at a height of not less than",
    "feedback": "200 m or 700 ft above ground or water"
  },
  {
    "question": "The following signal means that an aircraft wishes to give notice of difficulties which compel it to land without requiring immediate assistance",
    "feedback": "the repeated switching on and off of the landing lights"
  },
  {
    "question": "Above FL 290, flights operated under IFR in non-RVSM airspace, proceeding in the same direction are separated by:",
    "feedback": "4000 feet"
  },
  {
    "question": "The following minimum radar separation shall be provided between aircraft on the same localizer with additional longitudinal separation as required for wake turbulence:",
    "feedback": "3 NM."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following Annexes to the Chicago convention contains minimum specifications for the design of aerodromes?",
    "feedback": "Annex 14"
  },
  {
    "question": "If an international commercial air service is operated with a single pilot aircraft, what is the maximum age of the pilot?",
    "feedback": "59"
  },
  {
    "question": "The height of the marks under the wings of heavier than air aircraft shall be",
    "feedback": "at least 50 centimetres"
  },
  {
    "question": "The separation method whereby the vertical and horizontal separation may be reduced to half of the standard value is called:",
    "feedback": "Composite separation"
  },
  {
    "question": "The separation methods applied by ATC for controlled traffic are:",
    "feedback": "Vertical and horizontal separation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Whenever unlawful interference with an aircraft is suspected, and where automatic distinct display of SSR Mode A code 7500 and code 7700 is not provided, the radar controller shall attempt to verify this suspicion by :",
    "feedback": "Setting the SSR decoder to mode A code 7500 and thereafter to code 7700"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which chapter of the AIP can you find a list with \"location indicators\"?",
    "feedback": "GEN"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which code shall be used on mode \"A\" to provide recognition of an emergency aircraft?",
    "feedback": "Code 7700."
  },
  {
    "question": "A civil aircraft has been intercepted. According to SERA, what are correct actions to be carried out by the pilot in command of the civil aircraft?",
    "feedback": "Follow the intercepting aircraft and squawk 7700"
  },
  {
    "question": "Track separation between aircraft using the same VOR shall be applied requiring the aircraft to fly:",
    "feedback": "At least 15° separated at a distance of 15 NM or more from the facility."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the context of ICAO DOC 8168, the abbreviation \"DER\" stands for:",
    "feedback": "Departure end of runway."
  },
  {
    "question": "The height of the marks on lighter than air aircraft other than unmanned free balloons shall be",
    "feedback": "at least  50 centimetres"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the event of a delay for an uncontrolled flight for which an ATS flight plan has been submitted, the flight plan should be amended or a new ATS flight plan submitted and the old one canceled, when the delay exceeds the:",
    "feedback": "estimated off block time by 60 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Rome Convention and later amendments deals with :",
    "feedback": "Damage caused by foreign aircraft to third parties on the surface"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pilot in command of an aircraft:",
    "feedback": "may depart from air regulations for safety reasons only"
  },
  {
    "question": "Is the length of the outbound leg of a holding pattern always expressed in terms of time?",
    "feedback": "No, where DME is used it may be specified in terms of distance."
  },
  {
    "question": "The highest possible Flight Level for VFR flights, according to ICAO Annex 2, is:",
    "feedback": "FL200"
  },
  {
    "question": "During an arrival procedure under an IFR flight plan in VMC in airspace D, traffic avoidance is the responsibility of:",
    "feedback": "the pilot in command."
  },
  {
    "question": "A signalman will ask the pilot to apply parking brakes by the following signals:",
    "feedback": "Raise arm and hand, with fingers extended, horizontally in front of body , then clench fist"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is primarily responsible for the operation of the aircraft in accordance with the Rules of the Air (ICAO Annex 2)?",
    "feedback": "The pilot-in-command"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit responsible for promoting efficient organisation of search and rescue service in each SAR region is the:",
    "feedback": "Rescue Co-ordination Centre RCC"
  },
  {
    "question": "Low intensity obstacle lights on fixed objects are:",
    "feedback": "fixed red"
  },
  {
    "question": "How will a member state withdraw from the Tokyo Convention?",
    "feedback": "By informing ICAO"
  },
  {
    "question": "For a non-precision or circling approach, the Minimum Descent Height (MDH) cannot be lower than:",
    "feedback": "the Obstacle Clearance Height (OCH)"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the appropriate IFR Flight Level for a magnetic track of 070° in non-RVSM airspace?",
    "feedback": "FL330"
  },
  {
    "question": "The planned cruising speed for the first leg or all of the cruising portion of the flight must be entered in the speed box of a flight plan form. This speed is the:",
    "feedback": "true air speed (TAS)."
  },
  {
    "question": "One condition to initiate the distress phase is:",
    "feedback": "the aircraft and its occupants are threatened by grave and imminent danger or require immediate assistance"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the minimum obstacle clearance requirements in the primary area of the intermediate approach segment during an instrument approach procedure?",
    "feedback": "150 m (492 ft)"
  },
  {
    "question": "When may ATC assign a level previously occupied by another aircraft?",
    "feedback": "After the aircraft has reported vacating this level."
  },
  {
    "question": "Are CAT operators required to provide security training for their flight and/or cabin crew?",
    "feedback": "Yes, all such operators are required to provide this training for their crew members"
  },
  {
    "question": "In general, the main factor that determines the design of an instrument departure procedure is:",
    "feedback": "The terrain surrounding the aerodrome"
  },
  {
    "question": "The aircraft commander, when he has reasonable grounds to believe that a person has committed or is about to commit, on board the aircraft, an offense against penal law may",
    "feedback": "deliver such person to the competent authorities."
  },
  {
    "question": "The VMC minima for a VFR flight inside an ATS airspace classified as B, is :",
    "feedback": "8 km visibility when at or above 3050 m (10.000 ft) AMSL, and 1500 m horizontal and 300 m vertical from clouds"
  },
  {
    "question": "The units responsible for promoting efficient organization of search and rescue service are:",
    "feedback": "Rescue coordination centre and rescue sub-centres."
  },
  {
    "question": "The pre-flight actions for a flight leaving the local aerodrome area is to include a careful:",
    "feedback": "study of the available meteorological reports and forecasts for the route"
  },
  {
    "question": "To be able to execute a public transport flight, the minimum and maximum age (with ATPL) is:",
    "feedback": "21 and 64 years"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Convention of Tokyo applies to damage:",
    "feedback": "the above convention does not deal with this item"
  },
  {
    "question": "Aircraft \"A\" with an ATC clearance is flying in VMC conditions within a control area. Aircraft \"B\" with no ATC clearance is approaching at approximately the same altitude and on a converging course. Which has the right of way?",
    "feedback": "Aircraft \"B\" if \"A\" is on its left"
  },
  {
    "question": "The three entry sectors in a holding pattern have a zone of flexibility on either side of the sectors boundaries of:",
    "feedback": "5°"
  },
  {
    "question": "The abbreviation RNP means:",
    "feedback": "Required navigation performance."
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying from the USA to Germany. Overhead the UK, the pilot is told that the aircraft will be no longer allowed to enter Germany. All mentioned countries signed the International Aviation Convention. This situation is ....",
    "feedback": "legal, because each Contracting State has the right of sovereignty over its own airspace"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement regarding approach control service is correct ?",
    "feedback": "If it is anticipated that an aircraft has to hold for 30 minutes or more, an Expected Approach Time will be transmitted by the most expeditious means to the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "A defined rectangular area, selected or prepared as a suitable area over which an aeroplane may make a portion of its initial climb to a specified height is called:",
    "feedback": "Clearway"
  },
  {
    "question": "A series of red flashes from aerodrome control directed towards an aircraft on ground means:",
    "feedback": "taxi clear of landing area in use"
  },
  {
    "question": "Describe the common minimum dimensions of a radio altimeter operating area:",
    "feedback": "300 m x 60 m"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a holding pattern all turns are to be made at a :",
    "feedback": "rate of 3°per second or at a bank angle of 25°, which ever requires the lesser bank."
  },
  {
    "question": "Flight Information Service shall be provided to aircraft in order to avoid collision hazards when operating in airspace classes :",
    "feedback": "C, D, E, F, and G"
  },
  {
    "question": "Except in special circumstances determined by the public authorities concerned, when a passenger is passing through the territory of a contracting state and has to stay in that contracting state until the next flight for lack of facilities or any other circumstances, the contracting state where the international airport is located shall permit such a passenger to remain within its territory without requiring visas prior to the arrival when",
    "feedback": "the passenger is to leave that state within two (2) days from the day of his (her) arrival"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the \"PAPI\" system the pilot during an approach will see the two units nearest the runway as red and the two units farthest from the runway as white when:",
    "feedback": "On or close to the approach slope."
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot suffers a significant decrease in visual acuity, which is also causing chronic headaches. Consequently, he/she shall stop ....",
    "feedback": "exercising all the privileges of his/her licence"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"A publication issued by or with the authority of a State and containing aeronautical information of a lasting character essential to air navigation\" is the definition of:",
    "feedback": "Aeronautical Information Publication (AIP)."
  },
  {
    "question": "A \"precision approach\" is a direct instrument approach...",
    "feedback": "using bearing, elevation and distance information."
  },
  {
    "question": "Unless instructed otherwise by an air traffic controller, when passing through the transition layer, a pilot shall report the vertical position of the aircraft as:",
    "feedback": "altitude in a descent"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the relevant FCL requirements, the applicant for an ATPL(A) shall have demonstrated the ability to perform as pilot-in-command, the procedures and manoeuvres of an aeroplane type certificated for:",
    "feedback": "a minimum crew of two pilots under IFR"
  },
  {
    "question": "The aerodrome category determining the rescue and fire fighting equipment is based on the:",
    "feedback": "over-all length of the longest aeroplane normally using the aerodrome and its maximum fuselage width"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Class Rating SEP(L) includes the Single Pilot Single Engine Piston(A) Class Rating not requiring a Type Rating, plus",
    "feedback": "Touring Motor Gliders (TMG)"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a VFR-Flight which of the following cruising levels would you select under the following conditions: True track 358°, variation 3°E, deviation 2°W?",
    "feedback": "FL 65"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the Class of Airspace with the following conditions and services:\n\nIFR and VFR permitted\nAir Traffic Advisory Service: all participating IFR flights\nTraffic information: if requested for all flights",
    "feedback": "Airspace Class F"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which procedure do you follow if during an IFR flight in VMC you have two way communication failure?",
    "feedback": "Continue the flight maintaining VMC and land as soon as practicable."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the minimum separation between a LIGHT or HEAVY aircraft and a HEAVY aircraft taking off on parallel runways, separated by less than 760 m/2500 ft?",
    "feedback": "2 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which convention deals with the unification of rules related to damage caused by aircraft to third parties on the surface?",
    "feedback": "The Rome convention."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the mission statement of EASA?",
    "feedback": "EASA produces rules and regulations and promotes the highest common standards of civil aviation safety and environmental protection in Europe and worldwide."
  },
  {
    "question": "A glider is converging with an aircraft which is towing an object. Who has the right of way?",
    "feedback": "The glider has right of way"
  },
  {
    "question": "In ICAO Annex 14, Volume 1, the recommended runway width is specified by a combination of code numbers and letters, and is found in:",
    "feedback": "Chapter 3, Physical Characteristics"
  },
  {
    "question": "In accordance to EU Council Directive 2003/42, the following occurrences must be reported to the competent authorities:",
    "feedback": "All of the above."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the minimum time period for which a State's Aeronautical Information Service must be available for any given flight operating in its area of responsibility?",
    "feedback": "During the period the aircraft is in flight plus 2 hours before and after"
  },
  {
    "question": "Describe the physical characteristics of a radio-altimeter operating area:",
    "feedback": "On a radio altimeter operating area, slope changes should be avoided or kept to a minimum. Where slope changes cannot be avoided, the slope changes should be as gradual as practicable and abrupt changes or sudden reversals of slopes avoided. The rate of change between two consecutive slopes should not exceed 2 per cent per 30 m."
  },
  {
    "question": "The height of the marks on the fuselage (or equivalent structure) and on the vertical tail surfaces of heavier than air aircraft shall be",
    "feedback": "at least 30 centimetres"
  },
  {
    "question": "At least how many days in advance of the effective date must AIRAC information be distributed?",
    "feedback": "42"
  },
  {
    "question": "Any contracting state may denounce the Convention of Montreal by written notification to the depositary governments. The denounciation shall take effect :",
    "feedback": "6 months following the date on which notification is received by the Depositary Governments"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the conditions which allows to descend below the MDA on a circling approach is:",
    "feedback": "the required visual references have been established and can be maintained"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a runway is 2 000 metres in length, and taxi holding positions have not been established, aircraft shall not be held closer to the runway in use more than:",
    "feedback": "50 metres."
  },
  {
    "question": "During a VFR flight, you intend to overtake a slower aircraft, by changing your course....",
    "feedback": "to the right"
  },
  {
    "question": "Temporary, long-term modification (3 months or more) and the short-term extensive or graphical information are published as:",
    "feedback": "AIP Supplements"
  },
  {
    "question": "A complete position report transmitted by radiotelephony shall contain the following elements of information in the order listed:",
    "feedback": "aircraft identification, position, time, flight level or altitude, next position and time over and ensuing significant point"
  },
  {
    "question": "Normally, the maximum descent gradient, applicable in the final approach segment to ensure the required minimum obstacle clearance, is :",
    "feedback": "6,5%."
  },
  {
    "question": "During an instrument approach, followed by a missed approach, the minimum obstacle clearance (MOC) in the final phase of this missed approach is :",
    "feedback": "50 m (164 ft)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Track separation between aircraft using the same FIX shall be applied requiring the aircraft to fly:",
    "feedback": "At least 45° separated at a distance of 15 NM or more from the fix."
  },
  {
    "question": "With regard to EASA Part-FCL, explain the term \"competent authority\":",
    "feedback": "The competent authority shall be an authority designated by the Member State to whom a person applies for the issue of pilot licences or associated ratings or certificates"
  },
  {
    "question": "Aircraft equipped with red anti-collision lights may display them:",
    "feedback": "to attract attention to the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "A brief description of the service(s) responsible for Search and Rescue can be found in part",
    "feedback": "GEN"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the permanent body of ICAO being responsible to the Assembly?",
    "feedback": "The Council."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is a primary function of IATA?",
    "feedback": "To tackle critical issues in Aviation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What will be your action if you can not comply with a standard holding pattern?",
    "feedback": "inform the ATC immediately and request a revised clearance."
  },
  {
    "question": "(CPL) When an airline crew member, in the exercise of her/his duties, travels to another Contracting State as a passenger in order to join an aircraft, she/he must carry for identification purposes:",
    "feedback": "A CMC."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where does the initial section of a missed approach procedure end?",
    "feedback": "When established in the climb."
  },
  {
    "question": "What shall a pilot do after a TCAS RA (Resolution Advisory) manoeuvre?",
    "feedback": "Notify ATC that the aircraft is returning to the current clearance"
  },
  {
    "question": "When an aircraft will pass through the level of another aircraft on the same track, the following minimum longitudinal separation shall be provided:",
    "feedback": "15 minutes at the time the level is crossed."
  },
  {
    "question": "A flashing red light from control tower during an approach to land means:",
    "feedback": "The airport is unsafe, do not land"
  },
  {
    "question": "The regulatory material related to air safety and managed by EASA involves:",
    "feedback": "Hard law and soft law"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the appropriate IFR Flight Level for a magnetic track of 230° in RVSM airspace?",
    "feedback": "FL380"
  },
  {
    "question": "The longitudinal separation minima based on time between aircraft using the same cruising level, may be reduced, provided:",
    "feedback": "navigation aids permit frequent determination of the aircraft position and the speed of the preceding aircraft is higher than the one of the following aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the relevant Part-FCL requirements, the minimum age for the issue of an ATPL is",
    "feedback": "21 years"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which option corresponds to the mission statement of IATA?",
    "feedback": "IATA's mission is to represent, lead and serve the airline industry. IATA seeks to improve understanding of the industry among decision makers and increase awareness of the benefits that aviation brings to national and global economies. It fights for the interests of airlines across the globe, challenging unreasonable rules and charges, holding regulators and governments to account, and striving for sensible regulation"
  },
  {
    "question": "The lower limit of a TMA shall be established at a height above the ground or water of not less than",
    "feedback": "700 ft/200 m"
  },
  {
    "question": "On an IFR flight in airspace class D, you receive a traffic information from ATC, that a VFR flight is going to cross your flight path from right to left. Who has the right-of-way?",
    "feedback": "The VFR flight has the right-of-way."
  },
  {
    "question": "The applicant for an IR(A) shall hold a PPL (A) including a night qualification or CPL(A) and shall have completed at least 50 hours :",
    "feedback": "Cross country flight time as pilot-in-command in aeroplanes or helicopters of which at least 10 hours shall be in aeroplanes."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can you recognize that the edges or shoulders of an apron are non-load-bearing surfaces?",
    "feedback": "One pair of lines in the same colour of the taxiway centre line"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which occurrences require mandatory reporting, according to Regulation (EU) No 376/2014?",
    "feedback": "Occurrences which may represent a significant risk to aviation safety"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the functions ensured by a radar control unit for the provision of approach control service is:",
    "feedback": "To conduct surveillance radar approaches."
  },
  {
    "question": "Validity and renewal of airworthiness certificates shall be subject of the",
    "feedback": "Laws of the State of registry"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the relevant Part-FCL requirements, one of the privileges of the holder of a Commercial Pilot Licence aeroplane is to act as",
    "feedback": "pilot in command on any aeroplane engaged in operations other than commercial air transportation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cabotage refers to:",
    "feedback": "domestic air services"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the time estimated for the next reporting point differs from that notified to ATS, a revised estimate shall be notified to ATS if the time difference is in excess (±) of:",
    "feedback": "2 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Part-FCL, an applicant for an IR(A) shall hold a PPL(A) including a night qualification, if the IR privileges will be used at night, or CPL(A) and shall have completed at least 50 hours",
    "feedback": "The correct answers are: cross-country flight time as pilot-in-command in aeroplanes or helicopters of which at least 10 hours shall be in aeroplanes, instructional flight time as student pilot-in-command of aeroplanes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following standard instrument departures is not a straight departure?\n\nA) A departure where the initial departure track differs more than 20° from the runway alignment.\nB) A departure where the initial departure track differs more than 15° from the runway alignment.\nC) A departure where the initial departure track differs more than 10° from the runway alignment.\nD) A departure where the initial departure track differs more than 5° from the runway alignment.",
    "feedback": "A and B"
  },
  {
    "question": "What privilege does the first freedom of the air grant?",
    "feedback": "to fly across the territory of a state without landing in that state"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the relevant Part-FCL requirements, the holder of a pilot licence when acting as co-pilot performing under the supervision of the pilot in command the functions and duties of a pilot in command shall be credited:",
    "feedback": "in full with his flight time towards the total time required for higher grade of pilot licence"
  },
  {
    "question": "When it becomes apparent that an aircraft operating within controlled airspace is in difficulty, the decision to initiate the appropriate alert phases is the responsibility of:",
    "feedback": "Air Traffic Control"
  },
  {
    "question": "To cross lighted stop bars on the manoeuvring area of an aerodrome, the following applies:",
    "feedback": "An aircraft may only proceed further if the lights are switched off."
  },
  {
    "question": "Air traffic services unit clocks and other time recording devices shall be checked as necessary to ensure correct  time to within plus or minus",
    "feedback": "30 seconds of UTC at all times"
  },
  {
    "question": "In airspace Class C below 3050 m/10000 ft AMSL the maximum speed for flights under IFR is",
    "feedback": "not restricted"
  },
  {
    "question": "A so called \"Visual Approach\" can be performed by a flight under IFR:",
    "feedback": "when either part or all of an instrument approach procedure is not completed and the approach is executed with visual reference to the terrain"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of a spherical red marker with a diameter of 60 cm, displayed on or adjacent to an object, and giving the impression that it is suspended at low level in the air?",
    "feedback": "Overhead power lines or cables"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an instrument departure procedure the minimum obstacle clearance at the departure end of runway equals:",
    "feedback": "0 ft."
  },
  {
    "question": "Each Contracting State shall ensure that the appropriate Authority arranges for the supporting resources and facilities required by the aviation security services to be available:",
    "feedback": "at each airport serving international civil aviation"
  },
  {
    "question": "An overtaking aircraft is an aircraft that approaches another aircraft from the rear on a line forming an angle of less than:",
    "feedback": "70 degrees with the plane of symmetry of the latter"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements regarding Alerting service is correct?",
    "feedback": "Alerting Service and Flight Information Service are often provided by the same ATS unit"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the meaning of symbol 6 in the ground air visual signal code for use by survivors ?",
    "feedback": "Require medical assistance"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a precision approach, what is the maximum scale deflection tolerated according to EASA AIR OPS for the glide slope?",
    "feedback": "1/2"
  },
  {
    "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?",
    "feedback": "The ATIS is updated immediately when a significant change occurs"
  },
  {
    "question": "A contracting state which continues to require the presentation of a cargo manifest shall, apart from the information indicated in the heading of the format of the cargo manifest, not require more than the following item(s) :",
    "feedback": "The air waybill number; the number of packages related to each air waybill number and the nature of the goods"
  },
  {
    "question": "The light shown by an \"Aerodrome Identification Beacon\" at a land aerodrome shall be:",
    "feedback": "Green colour identification given by Morse Code."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which part of the Aeronautical Information Publication (AIP) contains Runway (RWY) physical characteristics, declared distances, approach lighting and runway lighting?",
    "feedback": "AD."
  },
  {
    "question": "The buffer area beyond the boundary of the holding area extends to:",
    "feedback": "5 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "During the climb-out phase of a flight the pilot in command becomes incapacitated. The co-pilot takes over control of the aircraft and decides that he will return for landing. What action has to be taken after landing?",
    "feedback": "This is a serious incident. The crew must follow the procedure relevant to an incident"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is correct with regard to the display of lights by an aircraft, according to SERA 3215?",
    "feedback": "All aircraft in flight and fitted with anti-collision lights shall display such lights also during the day"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\n\nAGL = above ground level\nAMSL = above mean sea level\nFL = flight level\n\nwithin uncontrolled airspace, the first usable level in IFR must provide a 500 ft margin above the following two levels:",
    "feedback": "3 000 ft AMSL or 1 000ft AGL."
  },
  {
    "question": "To be able to execute a public transport flight, the minimum and maximum age (with ATPL) is :",
    "feedback": "21 and 59 years"
  },
  {
    "question": "Subject to the technology available documents for entry and departure of aircraft:",
    "feedback": "are accepted in handwritten block lettering in ink"
  },
  {
    "question": "In areas where a separation minimum of 1000 ft. is applied up to FL 410, authorisation for VFR flight shall not be granted above which flight level?",
    "feedback": "FL 290."
  },
  {
    "question": "For planning purposes, an aerodrome is categorised by aerodrome reference code. This consists of two elements: A number, and a letter. What does the number relate to?",
    "feedback": "Take-off distance required for an aeroplane."
  },
  {
    "question": "When taxiing from the stand to the runway a person on the ground is seriously injured by the jet blast from the engines. How would this occurrence be described?",
    "feedback": "Accident"
  },
  {
    "question": "For which ICAO aircraft categories is the obstacle clearance altitude/height within an established visual manoeuvring (circling) area determined?",
    "feedback": "A, B, C, D, E"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot may expect instructions for a missed approach from Radar when the controller has not issued the landing clearance at the moment the aircraft is:",
    "feedback": "2 NM from the touchdown"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the meaning of the term \"Danger Area\"?",
    "feedback": "An airspace of defined dimensions within which activities dangerous to the flight of aircraft may exist at specified times"
  },
  {
    "question": "An Airbus A380 performs a visual approach at Rome Fiumicino. The aircraft is number 2 for the approach, behind an Airbus A320, and the A380 pilot reports that he/she has the A320 in sight.\nATC gives the A380 pilot the clearance to \"maintain separation\". In this situation, which option is correct as regards the wake turbulence separation between the A380 and the A320?",
    "feedback": "ATC is no longer required to apply wake turbulence separation between the A320 and the A380"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot may expect that lights on and in the vicinity of an aerodrome may be turned off, on condition that they can be brought back into operation before the expected arrival of an aircraft in at least:",
    "feedback": "one hour"
  },
  {
    "question": "Runway edge lights are:",
    "feedback": "fixed variable intensity unidirectional showing white or yellow"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is responsible to determine minimum flight altitudes for ATS routes?",
    "feedback": "Each State for ATS routes over their territory."
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Time Approach Procedure\" is used as necessary to expedite the approach of a number of arriving aircraft. This will be obtained requesting aircraft:",
    "feedback": "To pass the specified point inbound at the previously notified time."
  },
  {
    "question": "When an aircraft has sustained damage, the aircraft shall be allowed to resume its flight, if",
    "feedback": "the state of registry considers that the damage sustained is of a nature such that the aircraft is still airworthy"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main objectives for altimeter setting procedures are to provide adequate....",
    "feedback": "vertical separation between aircraft and adequate terrain clearance during all phases of flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "The convention signed by the states and moved by a desire to ensure adequate compensation for persons who suffer damage caused on the surface by foreign aircraft is :",
    "feedback": "the Rome Convention"
  },
  {
    "question": "An instrument rating is valid for",
    "feedback": "one year"
  },
  {
    "question": "The color identification of the contents of droppable containers and packages containing survival equipment should take the form of coloured streamers according to the following code:",
    "feedback": "Black for miscellaneous equipment."
  },
  {
    "question": "The informations concerning charges for aerodromes/heliports and Air Navigation Services are on the following part of the AIP",
    "feedback": "GEN"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a straight departure the initial track does not deviate from the alignment of the extended runway centre line by more than:",
    "feedback": "15 degrees"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is a stopway situated?",
    "feedback": "At the end of the TORA"
  },
  {
    "question": "A flight is operating in IMC under IFR, exactly on the current flight plan route.\n\nAt 18:36 UTC the radar controller gives the following instruction: \"Turn to heading 050, maintain heading 050 until further advised\". This message is acknowledged.\n\nAt 18:37 UTC a two way communication failure occurs. Radio communication can not be re-established.\n\nThe procedure to be followed is:",
    "feedback": "return to the current flight plan route"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which convention on international air navigation resulted in the agreements concerning the responsibilities with illegal acts committed on board aircraft?",
    "feedback": "the Tokyo Convention"
  },
  {
    "question": "Following an act of unlawful interference, if unable to communicate with ATC, the commander should, where possible:",
    "feedback": "proceed at a level which differs from the cruising levels normally used for IFR flight in the area by 300 m (1000 ft) if above FL290 or by 150 M (500 ft) if below FL 290"
  },
  {
    "question": "A strayed aircraft is an aircraft:",
    "feedback": "which has deviated significantly from its intended track or which reports that it is lost"
  },
  {
    "question": "You receive a clearance from ATC to climb to FL120, while passing altitude 2000 ft. Regarding the altimeter setting, you ......",
    "feedback": "remain on QNH until passing the transition altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "(CPL) What is the purpose of a CMC?",
    "feedback": "To provide identification of aircrew."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where two aircraft are established on adjacent parallel ILS localizers, what is the minimum radar separation permitted under mode 2 operations (Dependent Parallel Approaches)?",
    "feedback": "2 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Alerting Service is provided by:",
    "feedback": "The ATS unit responsible for the aircraft at that moment."
  },
  {
    "question": "Within the Annex to the ICAO convention that specifies dimensions of aerodromes is a specific dimension given for the approach light system for CAT 1 ILS. What should be the length of this approach light system?",
    "feedback": "900 metres"
  },
  {
    "question": "The State that shall judge whether a damaged aircraft is airworthy, as defined by the appropriate airworthiness requirements, is the....",
    "feedback": "State of Registry"
  },
  {
    "question": "You have landed at your planned destination aerodrome and are required to submit an arrival report to the appropriate air traffic services unit. The report needs to include which of the following information:\n1) Aircraft information2) Type of aircraft and operator3) Departure aerodrome or operating site4) Cargo manifest5) Arrival aerodrome6) Time of arrival7) Fuel on board",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 5, 6"
  },
  {
    "question": "A signalman (Marshaller) requests the pilot to engage brakes with the following signal:",
    "feedback": "raising arm and hand with fingers extended horizontally in front of body, then clench fist"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the vicinity of an aerodrome of intended landing or used for take-off, the vertical position of the aircraft shall be expressed in term of:",
    "feedback": "altitude above sea level at or below the transition altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "A special VFR clearance may be obtained from ATC for the following airspaces:",
    "feedback": "CTR."
  },
  {
    "question": "In which airspace classes has separation between IFR flights and VFR flights to be provided by ATC?",
    "feedback": "B, C."
  },
  {
    "question": "The take-off mass of MEDIUM aircraft is as follows:",
    "feedback": "Less than 136'000 kg but more than 7000 kg."
  },
  {
    "question": "When an unruly passenger endangers the safety of the aircraft, the aircraft commander ....",
    "feedback": "may disembark the unruly passenger in the territory of any State"
  },
  {
    "question": "The MSA provides an obstacle clearance of at least 300 m (984 ft) within a circle, associated with the homing facility for the approach procedure of that aerodrome.\n\nThe circle has a radius of",
    "feedback": "25 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The centre line and crossbar lights of a precision approach Category I lighting system are fixed lights, showing variable intensity in the following colour:",
    "feedback": "white"
  },
  {
    "question": "The longitudinal separation minima based on time between aircraft at same cruising level where navigation aids permit frequent determination of position and speed and the preceding aircraft is maintaining a true airspeed of 40 kt or more faster than the succeeding aircraft, is:",
    "feedback": "3 minutes."
  },
  {
    "question": "On an aerodrome equipped with parallel runways, the designation number of each runway is supplemented as follows:",
    "feedback": "in case of two parallel runways by the letter \"L\" and \"R\" in the sequence from left to right."
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the figure:\nWhat does the signal from the signalman (marshaller) situated at the aircraft wing tip, mean?",
    "feedback": "The aircraft movement on/off a parking position would be unobstructed"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"An area symmetrical about the extended runway centre line and adjacent to the end of the strip primarily intended to reduce the risk of damage to an aeroplane undershooting or overrunning the runway\" is the definition for:",
    "feedback": "Runway end safety area."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Cabotage?",
    "feedback": "domestic air services by an operator within another state"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to ICAO Annex 14 Volume I, which of the following must be frangible?\n1) Fixed objects when marked by markers2) Stopway edge markers3) Taxiway edge markers4) Unpaved runway edge markers",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The loading limitations shall include :",
    "feedback": "all limiting mass, centres of gravity position, mass distributions and floor loadings"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the colour of runway edge lights?",
    "feedback": "white"
  },
  {
    "question": "When surveillance radar approaches are to be continued to the threshold of the runway transmission should not be interrupted for intervals of more than five seconds while the aircraft is within a distance of from touch down of:",
    "feedback": "4 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "6th Freedom of the Air is:",
    "feedback": "A combination of Freedoms 3 and 4. Revenue traffic flown between two treaty partner nations (C to A) through carriers base nation (B)."
  },
  {
    "question": "According to ICAO Annex 8, a certificate of airworthiness shall be renewed or shall remain valid subject to the:",
    "feedback": "Laws of the State of registry"
  },
  {
    "question": "During cruise, the pilots receive an ACAS Traffic Advisory from an aircraft flying at a lower altitude, climbing towards their altitude. According to ICAO DOC 8168, they should ....",
    "feedback": "use all available information to prepare for appropriate action if a Resolution Advisory occurs"
  },
  {
    "question": "Definition of Security, the ICAO Annex 17, is a combination of measures...",
    "feedback": "and human and material resources intended to safeguard international civil aviation against acts of unlawful interference"
  },
  {
    "question": "On final approach, on a normal glide path the number of red lights visible of a PAPI are:",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is obligating for members of ICAO ?",
    "feedback": "ICAO must be informed about differences from the standards in any of the Annexes to the convention"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an offset entry into an omnidirectional racetrack procedure, the time on the 30° offset track is limited to:",
    "feedback": "1 minute 30 seconds."
  },
  {
    "question": "Pilots of controlled flights shall inform the appropriate ATS whenever the average TAS at cruising level varies or is expected to vary from the TAS given in the flight plan by:",
    "feedback": "5%"
  },
  {
    "question": "The number of stripes on each side of the centre line of a runway which has a width of 45 m is:",
    "feedback": "6"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to ICAO DOC 8168, before taking off, one altimeter shall be set to the latest ...... altimeter setting for the aerodrome",
    "feedback": "QNH"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of a runway strip?",
    "feedback": "To minimize the risk of aircraft damage at runway excursion and to protect aircraft flying over it during take-off or landing operations"
  },
  {
    "question": "For flights under IFR within advisory airspace. a flight plan:",
    "feedback": "shall be submitted. Changes to the flight plan have to be reported"
  },
  {
    "question": "Each member state should designate an appropriate authority with its administration to be responsible for the development implementation and maintenance of a national aviation security programme. This programme should apply :",
    "feedback": "to all international civil air transport including aircraft engaged solely in the carriage of cargo and yet to domestic flights at the discretion of each member state"
  },
  {
    "question": "To acknowledge mode and code setting instructions, pilots shall:",
    "feedback": "Read back the mode and code to be set"
  },
  {
    "question": "Standard airway holding pattern below 14 000 ft ?",
    "feedback": "Right hand turns / 1 minute outbound"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to EASA Aircrew regulation, licence holder do not exercise the privileges of their licenses, related ratings or authorizations at any time when they are aware of any decrease in their medical fitness which might render them unable to safely exercise those privileges. They shall without undue delay seek the advice of the AME when have been admitted to hospital or medical clinic for:",
    "feedback": "Any period"
  },
  {
    "question": "The privilege to fly across the territory of another participating state without landing is called:",
    "feedback": "the first freedom of the air"
  },
  {
    "question": "The letter \"L\" is written in the wake turbulence box of a flight plan form when the maximum certified take-off weight of an aircraft is less than or equal to:",
    "feedback": "7 000 kg."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following steps and which order correctly defines the emergency phase?\n1) Alert2) Distress3) Emergency4) Alarm5) Uncertainty",
    "feedback": "5, 1, 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the minimum wake turbulence separation criteria when a light aircraft is taking off behind a medium aircraft and both are using the same runway ?",
    "feedback": "2 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "A NOTAM shall be issued in....",
    "feedback": "English and distributed by the Aeronautical Fixed Service (AFS)"
  },
  {
    "question": "In areas where a vertical separation minimum (VSM) of 300 metres (1000 ft) is applied between FL 290 and FL 410 inclusive, an aircraft on a magnetic track of 350 would be expected to fly at:",
    "feedback": "FL 400"
  },
  {
    "question": "In airspace Class B below 3050 m/10000 ft AMSL the maximum speed for flights under VFR and IFR is",
    "feedback": "not restricted"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to ICAO Annex 2 or EASA SERA.5015, what is the minimum required equipment for an IFR flight?",
    "feedback": "It must be suitable and appropriate for the route to be flown"
  },
  {
    "question": "An Aerodrome Reference Point ARP is defined as the:",
    "feedback": "Designated geographical location of the aerodrome"
  },
  {
    "question": "A ATPL(A) gives the privileges as...",
    "feedback": "PPL(A), LAPL(A), CPL(A), ATPL(A), PIC on commercial flights"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Special Air Report comprises a number of sections.\nIn section I the pilot fills in :",
    "feedback": "a position report, including aircraft identification, height, position and time ;"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the figure. A marshaller abruptly extends arms and wands to top of head, crossing wands. What does this mean?",
    "feedback": "Emergency stop"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the maximum allowed certified take-off mass of an aircraft to be considered \"LIGHT\", with regard to the wake turbulence category?",
    "feedback": "7000 kg"
  },
  {
    "question": "A horizontal white dumb-bell when displayed on a signal area of an aerodrome means:",
    "feedback": "Aircraft are required to land, take off and taxi on runways and taxiways only."
  },
  {
    "question": "In which area of Air Traffic Control in Europe does Eurocontrol have a logical and operationally essential role to play?",
    "feedback": "Air Traffic Flow Management in Europe."
  },
  {
    "question": "You may act as a flight instructor to carry out flight instruction for the issue of a PPL",
    "feedback": "With a theoretical CPL examination plus flight instructor rating"
  },
  {
    "question": "Referring to the operational aspects in the unlawful seizure acts, it can be said:",
    "feedback": "The contracting States will make provisions to ensure that an aircraft affected by an unlawful seizure act, which has landed in their territory, would be retained, unless its departure is justified  to protect lives."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where no minimum flight altitudes have been established for IFR flights, which statement concerning minimum flight altitudes for IFR flights is correct?",
    "feedback": "Over high terrain or in mountainous areas, at a level which is at least 600 m (2000 ft.) above the highest obstacle located within 8 km of the estimated position of the aircraft."
  },
  {
    "question": "The International Civil Aviation Organisation (ICAO) establishes:",
    "feedback": "standards and recommended international practices for contracting member states."
  },
  {
    "question": "RNP types shall be determined on the basis of:",
    "feedback": "communication, navigation and air traffic services provided in the airspace concerned"
  },
  {
    "question": "Medical requirements are contained in the following EASA Part:",
    "feedback": "Part-MED"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a person is found inadmissible and is returned to the operator for transport away from the territory of the state, the operator :",
    "feedback": "shall not be preclude from recovering from such person any transportation costs arising from his (her) inadmissibility"
  },
  {
    "question": "What can the commander of an aircraft do if he has reason to believe that a person has or is about to commit an offence in the aeroplane that is against penal law?",
    "feedback": "all of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "The height of the transition altitude above the aerodrome shall be as low as possible but normally not less than:",
    "feedback": "3000 ft AGL"
  },
  {
    "question": "The speed limitation for IFR flights inside ATS airspace classified as C, when flying below 3.050 m (10.000 ft) AMSL, is :",
    "feedback": "Not applicable"
  },
  {
    "question": "Figure 5 indicates:",
    "feedback": "a runway intersection sign"
  },
  {
    "question": "The crew of an intercepted aircraft shall immediately attempt to establish radio communication with the intercepting aircraft or with the appropriate intercept control unit by making a general call on the frequency:",
    "feedback": "121.5 MHz.  If no contact has been established, and if practicable, repeat this call on the frequency 243 MHz"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft operating under VFR, above the sea at altitudes between 4500 ft and 9000 ft AMSL, outside controlled airspace shall maintain a distance from cloud of at least:",
    "feedback": "1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight visibility of 5 km"
  },
  {
    "question": "On aerodromes aircraft taxying on the manoeuvring area of an aerodrome shall give way to:",
    "feedback": "aircraft taking off or about to take off"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to ICAO Annex 13, a contracting state is obligated to investigate an accident/incident:",
    "feedback": "within its state but not over high seas"
  },
  {
    "question": "When should the flight crew be provided with information about the transition level?",
    "feedback": "Before starting the initial approach to an aerodrome"
  },
  {
    "question": "If radio communication failure is experienced on an IFR flight in IMC, generally the pilot shall:",
    "feedback": "Try to get contact on other frequencies either ground or aircraft stations - Transmit blind indicating important details required 2 times."
  },
  {
    "question": "When can a pilot deviate from a Resolution Advisory (RA)?",
    "feedback": "If following such RA would jeopardize the safe operation of the flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ICAO annex which deals with entry and departure of cargo and other articles on international flights is :",
    "feedback": "annex 9"
  },
  {
    "question": "An ATS unit will issue clearances for the purpose of",
    "feedback": "Achieving separation between controlled flights"
  },
  {
    "question": "ILS obstacle clearance surfaces are established under the assumption that the pilot does not allow the aircraft to deviate from the centreline by more than:",
    "feedback": "half a scale deflection after being established on the track"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to ICAO DOC 8168 PANS-OPS, the QNH should be made available to a departing aircraft ......",
    "feedback": "in taxi clearances prior take-off"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the relevant FCL requirements, an instrument rating is valid for:",
    "feedback": "one year"
  },
  {
    "question": "A minimum separation of at least 2 minutes shall be applied between a LIGHT or MEDIUM aircraft and a HEAVY aircraft taking off behind, using parallel runways:",
    "feedback": "separated by less than 760 m"
  },
  {
    "question": "When is deviation from the Rules of the Air permitted?",
    "feedback": "Only in the interests of flight safety"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why must the airline issue a ticket?",
    "feedback": "To establish a contract"
  },
  {
    "question": "The identification of each prohibited, restricted and danger area shall be composed by :",
    "feedback": "The nationality letters for location indicators assigned to the state or territory, followed the letters P. R and D and figures"
  },
  {
    "question": "When pilot licence holders have reached the age of 40 and are engaged in single-pilot commercial air transport operations carrying passengers, the validity of a Class 1 medical examination is reduced in accordance with the relevant medical requirements from:",
    "feedback": "12 to 6 months"
  },
  {
    "question": "Whenever ATIS is provided, the broadcast information shall be updated",
    "feedback": "immediately a significant change occurs"
  },
  {
    "question": "(CPL) If an aircraft subjected to an act of unlawful seizure has landed on its territory, each Contracting State shall:",
    "feedback": "a and c."
  },
  {
    "question": "The provisions for a flight under VFR in Class E airspace are",
    "feedback": "Services provided : Traffic Information as far as practical; ATC Clearance : not required"
  },
  {
    "question": "Above 3050 m (10000 ft) AMSL, the VMC minima for VFR flights in all classes of airspace (except class A) are:",
    "feedback": "8 km visibility, 1500 m horizontal and 1000 ft vertical distance from clouds ;"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of these runway designators is not approved for operational use?",
    "feedback": "Designator D"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pattern \"A\" runway holding position marking shall be supplemented at a taxiway/runway intersection with a ......",
    "feedback": "runway designation sign"
  },
  {
    "question": "The length of an approach lighting system for a precision approach runway CAT II is:",
    "feedback": "900 m"
  },
  {
    "question": "The longitudinal separation minima based on distance using DME, and each aircraft \"on track\" uses DME stations, is:",
    "feedback": "20 NM."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the missed approach point in an instrument approach procedure?",
    "feedback": "It is the point where the pilot would initiate a missed approach, if the approach cannot be continued"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of an aircraft accident investigation shall be:",
    "feedback": "The prevention of accidents."
  },
  {
    "question": "May further ratings under Part-FCL requirements be obtained by other States than the State of licence issue and if yes, by whom are such ratings entered into the licence?",
    "feedback": "Yes, ratings may be obtained by any EASA Member State, they will be entered into the licence by State of licence issue."
  },
  {
    "question": "The names of all separate segments that can be part of an instrument approach procedure are:",
    "feedback": "Arrival, initial, intermediate, final, missed approach"
  },
  {
    "question": "Contracting states shall carry out the handling, forwarding and clearance of airmail and shall comply with the documentary procedures as prescribed :",
    "feedback": "in the Acts in force of the Universal Postal Union"
  },
  {
    "question": "The minimum separation of a MEDIUM aircraft taking-off from the same runway behind a HEAVY aircraft is:",
    "feedback": "2 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is considered to be maintaining its assigned level as long as the SSR mode C derived level information indicated that it is within:",
    "feedback": "+/- 300 ft of the assigned level."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following correctly describes runway end lights?",
    "feedback": "Fixed; uni-directional; red."
  },
  {
    "question": "The transfer of an aircraft from one ATC unit to another is done :",
    "feedback": "by agreement with the receiving unit."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which State ensures the existence of a continuing structural integrity programme to ensure the airworthiness of the aeroplane above 5700 kg certificated take-off mass?",
    "feedback": "The State of Design"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ASHTAM provides information about the status of activity of a volcano by publishing a",
    "feedback": "colour code"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a State required to do regarding the aeroplane which has been unlawfully interfered with when it lands?",
    "feedback": "The contracting States will make provisions to ensure that an aircraft affected by an unlawful seizure act which has landed in their territory, would be detained on the ground, unless to do so would prejudice human life"
  },
  {
    "question": "Runway markings shall be:",
    "feedback": "White"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ground-air signals code for survivors: What is the meaning of an X displayed on the ground?",
    "feedback": "Require medical assistance."
  },
  {
    "question": "An EASA implementing rule, adopted by the European Commission, is considered a/an:",
    "feedback": "hard law"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the event that a controlled flight inadvertently deviates from its track given in the current flight plan, action should be taken in order to:",
    "feedback": "adjust the heading of aircraft to regain track as soon as practicable"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ICAO annex which deals with entry and departure of persons and their baggage in international flights is :",
    "feedback": "annex 9"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft designed and manufactured in the United States of America (USA), registered and operated in the United Kingdom (UK), and having a maximum mass of 10 tonnes, crashes in France.\nAccording to ICAO Annex 13, which States/organisation(s) must be notified of the accident and by whom?",
    "feedback": "France must notify the UK, the USA, and ICAO"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT an international distress frequency ?",
    "feedback": "2430 KHz"
  },
  {
    "question": "The complete CAT I/Calvert type of approach light system (with additional crossbars) consists of:",
    "feedback": "a centre line with 5 crossbars"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the figure: What does this signal from the marshaller mean?",
    "feedback": "Set brakes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Under the terms of the Tokyo Convention of 1963, what is a contracting state required to do in the event of an act of unlawful seizure occuring within the territory of that state?",
    "feedback": "the state shall take all appropriate measures to restore control of the aircraft to its lawful commander, or to preserve his control of the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "For commercial pilot licence aeroplane the applicant shall have completed in aeroplanes not less than if the privileges of the licence are to be exercised at night",
    "feedback": "5 hours of night flight time including 5 take offs and 5 landings as pilot in command"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft which is not engaged in scheduled international air services and which is making a flight to or through any designated airport of a Contracting State and is admitted temporarily free of duty shall be allowed to remain within that State without security for customs duty.",
    "feedback": "For a period to be established by that State"
  },
  {
    "question": "Air traffic control service is provided for the purpose of",
    "feedback": "Preventing collisions between aircraft, between aircraft and obstacles on the manoeuvring area and expediting and maintaining an orderly flow of air traffic"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does a signalman (marshaller) request the pilot to proceed to the next signalman or as directed by tower/ground control?",
    "feedback": "Pointing both arms upward, moving and extending arms outward to sides of body and pointing with wands to direction signalman or taxi area"
  },
  {
    "question": "The units providing Air Traffic Services are",
    "feedback": "Area Control Centre - Flight Information Centre - Approach Control Office - Aerodrome Control Tower and Air Traffic Services reporting office."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which does ATC Term \"Radar contact\" signify?",
    "feedback": "Your aircraft has been identified on the radar display and radar flight instructions will be provided until radar identification is terminated."
  },
  {
    "question": "The surveillance radar approach shall be terminated at a distance of 2 NM from the touchdown except when as determined by the appropriate ATS authority, the accuracy of the radar equipment permits to be continued to a prescribed point less than 2 NM from the touchdown. In this case distance and level information shall be given at each",
    "feedback": "half NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following Annexes to the Chicago convention contains international standards and recommended practices for air traffic services (ATS)?",
    "feedback": "Annex 11"
  },
  {
    "question": "Using the ground - air visual signal code, the letter similar to the symbol meaning \"REQUIRE MEDICAL ASSISTANCE\" is :",
    "feedback": "6"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"Aerodrome Reference Code\" is a code composed of two elements which are related to the aeroplane performance characteristics and dimensions. These elements are a combination of a number and a letter as in the example under listed:",
    "feedback": "2B."
  },
  {
    "question": "How is a paved pre-threshold area which is greater than 60 m in length but not suitable for use by aircraft, marked?",
    "feedback": "By yellow chevrons pointing towards the threshold."
  },
  {
    "question": "(CPL) The minimum age for a CPL (A) shall be at least:",
    "feedback": "18 years."
  },
  {
    "question": "The ASHTAM provides information on the status of activity of a volcano when a change in its activity is, or is expected to be of operational significance. This information is provided using the volcano level of colour code. When volcanic eruption in progress or volcano dangerous, eruption likely, with ash plume/cloud is reported above FL 250 or is expected to rise above FL 250, the level of alert colour code is",
    "feedback": "RED"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the sign depict?",
    "feedback": "Road-holding position"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which letter is used in a flight plan to indicate that the flight commences in accordance with IFR and subsequently changes to VFR?",
    "feedback": "Y"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the relevant Part-FCL requirements, the applicant for an ATPL(A) shall have demonstrated the ability to perform as pilot-in-command, the procedures and manoeuvres of an aeroplane type certificated for:",
    "feedback": "A minimum crew of two pilots under IFR"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Third Freedom of the Air is the right or privilege, in respect of scheduled international air services granted by one State to another State....",
    "feedback": "to put down, in the territory of the first State, traffic coming from the home State of the carrier"
  },
  {
    "question": "Missed approach procedures are normally based on a nominal missed approach climb gradient of:",
    "feedback": "2.5%"
  },
  {
    "question": "During an instrument approach, followed by a missed approach, the minimum obstacle clearance (MOC) in the intermediate phase of this missed approach is :",
    "feedback": "30 m (98 ft)"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot may expect to receive the clearance to land or any alternative clearance before the aircraft reaches a distance from touch down of:",
    "feedback": "2 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The speed limitation for IFR flights inside ATS airspace classified as E, when flying below 3.050 m (10.000 ft) AMSL, is :",
    "feedback": "250 KT IAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "A significant change in the mean surface wind direction is reported to the pilot when the mean crosswind component changes by more than:",
    "feedback": "5 kt/9 km/h"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pilots shall not operate the SSR special position indicator (IDENT) feature unless:",
    "feedback": "Requested by ATC."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which convention on international air navigation resulted in the agreements concerning the responsibilities with illegal acts committed on board aircraft?",
    "feedback": "The Convention of Tokyo."
  },
  {
    "question": "The ICAO Annex 17 comprise rules in order to establish security measures for passengers:",
    "feedback": "Cabin baggage, checked baggage, cargo and other goods, access control and airport design"
  },
  {
    "question": "The colour of a runway designation marking on a paved runway shall be",
    "feedback": "White."
  },
  {
    "question": "Describe the position of a radio altimeter operating area:",
    "feedback": "in the pre-threshold area"
  },
  {
    "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:",
    "feedback": "green"
  },
  {
    "question": "A notice containing information concerning flight safety, air navigation, technical, administration or legislative matters and originated at the AIS of a state is called:",
    "feedback": "Aeronautical Information Circular (AIC)."
  },
  {
    "question": "In areas where a vertical separation of 2000 ft. has to be applied above FL 290, which group of the following flight levels contains odd flight levels only?",
    "feedback": "FL 410, FL 330"
  },
  {
    "question": "When, in air space where VFR are permitted, the pilot in command of an IFR flight wishes to continue his flight in accordance with visual flight rules, until the destination is reached:\n1 He must inform the control unit (\"cancel IFR\")\n2 He must request and obtain clearance.\n3 He may request his IFR flight plan to be changed to a VFR flight plan.\n4 The flight plan automatically becomes a VFR flight plan.\nThe correct combination of statements is:",
    "feedback": "1 and 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which letter is used in a flight plan to indicate that the flight commences in accordance with IFR and subsequently changes to VFR?",
    "feedback": "Y"
  },
  {
    "question": "During flight below the transition altitude, the altimeter of an aircraft shall be set to",
    "feedback": "QNH and its vertical position is expressed in terms of altitude."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the event of a delay of a controlled flight, the submitted flight plan should be amended or cancelled and a new flight plan submitted when the delay is in excess of:",
    "feedback": "30 minutes of the estimated off block time"
  },
  {
    "question": "For an instrument runway, how far from the centre line of a runway is a \"runway vacated\" sign positioned?",
    "feedback": "At the end of the ILS/MLS sensitive area."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an AIP amendment?",
    "feedback": "The publication of permanent changes to the information contained in the AIP"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where does the missed approach procedure start?",
    "feedback": "At the missed approach point."
  },
  {
    "question": "Contracting States shall establish a rescue co-ordination centre:",
    "feedback": "In each search and rescue region."
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft making a radar approach should be directed to consider executing a missed approach if the aircraft is not visible on the radar display for any significant interval during the :",
    "feedback": "Last 2 NM of the approach"
  },
  {
    "question": "The correct statement about the obligation of a carrier to carry away any non-admitted person from the territory of a Contracting State is:",
    "feedback": "The obligation of the operator shall terminate, when such a person has been legally admitted for entry into a State"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the instructions received by radio from any sources are in conflict with those given by visual signals from an intercepting aircraft, the intercepted aircraft shall:",
    "feedback": "follow the instructions of the intercepting aircraft and request immediate clarification"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a passenger ticket?",
    "feedback": "A form of contract between airline and passenger"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is/are required if a stop bar is not provided at a runway entrance and the runway is intended to be used in RVR conditions less than 550 m?",
    "feedback": "Runway guard lights."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where should an intermediate holding position be established?",
    "feedback": "Between two paved taxiways. It shall consist of markings"
  },
  {
    "question": "The STOPWAY is a defined rectangular area on the ground at the end of take-off run available prepared as a suitable area where:",
    "feedback": "An aircraft can be stopped in the case of an abandoned take-off."
  },
  {
    "question": "A change from instrument flight rules (IFR) to visual flight rules (VFR) is only acceptable when VFR is permitted in that airspace and when:",
    "feedback": "the change is initiated by the PIC with a message containing the specific expression \"cancelling my IFR flight\""
  },
  {
    "question": "The applicant for ATPL (A) shall have completed as a pilot of aeroplane at least 1500 hours of flight time, including 500 hours in multi-pilot operations",
    "feedback": "on aeroplanes type certificated in accordance with CS/FAR 25 or CS/FAR 23."
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is taxiing on the movement area with the purpose to reach the refueling station. What are the rules it should follow while on the movement area?",
    "feedback": "General rules and local aerodrome rules"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane exits the runway and the aeroplane becomes stuck in the mud. What kind of occurrence is it and what action should be taken by the Commander?",
    "feedback": "It is an incident. The Commander must inform the operator using the normal procedure."
  },
  {
    "question": "A defined rectangular area on the ground at the end of take-off run available prepared as a suitable area in which an aircraft can be stopped in the case of an abandoned take-off is called:",
    "feedback": "Stopway"
  },
  {
    "question": "The vertical position of an aircraft at or above the transition level with altimeter setting 1013.25 hPa shall be expressed in terms of:",
    "feedback": "flight level"
  },
  {
    "question": "Contracting States have the obligation to inform ICAO about:",
    "feedback": "differences and/or deviations from the standards with the Annexes to the convention"
  },
  {
    "question": "One minute separation may be used between departing aircraft if they are to fly on tracks diverging by at least:",
    "feedback": "45° immediately after take-off."
  },
  {
    "question": "Obstacle clearance for an ILS approach is based on the assumption that the pilot does not deviate from the centre line more than :",
    "feedback": "half scale deflection of the localizer indicator."
  },
  {
    "question": "What may trigger a NOTAM to be emitted?\n1) Long duration work on the aerodrome2) Work or reparation on the fuel feeding area3) High safety level that increases the time at the security checks4) Strong solar radiations5) Epidemics outbreak that requires the passengers for new vaccine6) Withdrawal, change or new lights on the aerodrome7) Work on the manoevuring area that does not impede the aircraft movements8) Changes in aerodrome designation signs",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4, 5, 8"
  },
  {
    "question": "An air traffic control unit :",
    "feedback": "may ask an aircraft to temporarily change its call sign for safety reasons when there is a risk of confusion between two or more similar call signs."
  },
  {
    "question": "A Control Area (CTA) is a controlled airspace extending upwards from",
    "feedback": "a specified limit above ground or water"
  },
  {
    "question": "The licensing authority shall determine whether experience as pilot under instruction in a synthetic flight trainer which it has approved, is acceptable as part of the total flight time of 1500 hours (ATPL). Credit for such experience shall be limited to a maximum of:",
    "feedback": "100 hours, of which not more than 25 hours shall have been acquired in a flight procedure trainer or basic instrument flight trainer"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to ICAO DOC 8168, the abbreviation \"VNAV\" means:",
    "feedback": "Vertical Navigation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the abbreviation OIS mean?",
    "feedback": "Obstacle identification surface."
  },
  {
    "question": "The designation for the part of the AIP that contains a brief description of areas and/or routes for which meteorological service is provided is",
    "feedback": "GEN"
  },
  {
    "question": "You are a passenger travelling internationally for a holiday in an ICAO contracting state. In your travel documentation you have a valid passport and a visa recognized by the state you seek to enter. Upon arrival, according to Annex 9, ......",
    "feedback": "the state shall not require from you any other document or identification"
  },
  {
    "question": "As part of the total flight time requirement of 1500 hours for the issue of the ATPL in accordance with the relevant Part-FCL requirements, up to 100 hours may have been completed in FFS or FNPT.\n\nCredit for experience on a FNPT shall be limited to a maximum of:",
    "feedback": "25 hours"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Convention of Rome 1933/1952 for the Unification of certain Rules Relating to Damage caused by Aircraft was established in order to define the liability in case of damage:",
    "feedback": "to third parties on the surface"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is defined as: \"A control area or portion thereof established in the form of a corridor equipped with navigation aids\"?",
    "feedback": "An airway."
  },
  {
    "question": "The pilot-in-command of an aircraft:\n1) must comply immediately to all instructions received from ATC2) is responsible only if he is the pilot flying3) may deviate from air regulations for safety reasons4) may be exempt from air regulations in order to comply to an ATC instruction5) may ask for the modification of an unsatisfactory clearance\nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding Aerodrome Flight Information (AFIS) :",
    "feedback": "it can only supply limited services to the users and under no circumstances may it supply ATC services."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the correct answer with regard to definitions, according to EASA?",
    "feedback": "Guidance Material (GM) is non-binding explanatory and interpretation material on how to achieve the requirements contained (amongst others) in the Basic Regulation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Repetitive flight plans (RPL's) shall be used for flights operated regularly on the same day(s) of consecutive weeks and :",
    "feedback": "On at least ten occasions or every day over a period of at least ten consecutive days"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does EASA Basic Regulation refer to?",
    "feedback": "It refers to binding legal obligations and non-binding specifications"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft taxiing on the manoeuvring area of an aerodrome shall give way to",
    "feedback": "aircraft taking off or about to take off"
  },
  {
    "question": "A separation minimum shall be applied between a light or MEDIUM aircraft and a HEAVY aircraft and between a LIGHT aircraft and a MEDIUM aircraft when the heavier aircraft is making a low or missed approach and the lighter aircraft is utilizing an opposite direction runway for take off, this minimum is :",
    "feedback": "3 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "The responsibility to institute an investigation into the circumstances of an accident rests with:",
    "feedback": "The State of Occurrence."
  },
  {
    "question": "If an ATC clearance is not suitable to the pilot in command of an aircraft:",
    "feedback": "He may request and, if practicable, obtain an amended clearance."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which body of ICAO finalizes the Standard and Recommended Practices (SARPS) for submission and adoption?",
    "feedback": "The Air Navigation Commission."
  },
  {
    "question": "When conducting a surveillance radar approach, the radar controller shall terminate the surveillance radar approach, except as determined by the appropriate ATS authority, at a distance of:",
    "feedback": "2 NM from touchdown."
  },
  {
    "question": "When IFR flights are cleared to fly maintaining own separation while in VMC, the following shall apply:\n\nA) The clearance shall be for a specified portion of the flight at or below 10'000 ft., during climb or descent.\nB) The clearance shall be for a specified portion of the flight at or below 10'000 ft., during cruise, climb or descent.\nC) A pilot may be required by ATC to fly maintaining own separation while in VMC if no other means for the provision of separation are available.\nD) The procedure may be applied during the hours of daylight only.",
    "feedback": "A and D."
  },
  {
    "question": "When \"Secondary Surveillance Radar\" (SSR) is not available, the pilot may be requested by ATC to execute one or more heading changes for radar identification. The requested changes to be expected are in the order of:",
    "feedback": "30 degrees or more"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is correct regarding an AMC (Acceptable Means of Compliance)?",
    "feedback": "It is not binding and other means may be utilised if preferred to demonstrate compliance with the applicable requirements"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft which is intercepted by another aircraft shall set its transponder to:",
    "feedback": "Mode A, Code 7700 unless otherwise instructed by the appropriate ATS unit."
  },
  {
    "question": "COSPAS-SARSAT is:",
    "feedback": "a and c."
  },
  {
    "question": "When revalidating a type rating for a helicopter or aeroplane, during what period should this be conducted?",
    "feedback": "Within the 3 months immediately preceding the expiry date of the rating"
  },
  {
    "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated ?",
    "feedback": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported values"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Part-FCL, the privileges of the holder of an unrestricted FI(A) rating are to conduct flight instruction for the issue of a CPL(A):",
    "feedback": "Provided that the FI(A) has completed at least 500 hours of flight time as a pilot of aeroplanes including at least 200 hours of flight instruction"
  },
  {
    "question": "While taxying an aircraft receives the following light signal from the control tower : series of red flashes. This signal means that the aircraft :",
    "feedback": "must vacate the landing area in use."
  },
  {
    "question": "Annex 14 to the convention on international civil aviation contains SARPS for",
    "feedback": "Aerodromes."
  },
  {
    "question": "On June 1, 2009, an aircraft crashed into the South Atlantic Ocean. The crash happened over international water, and the location of the accident cannot definitely be established as being in the territory of any State. The aircraft was registered in France and departed from Brazil. When contact was lost, the aircraft was flying over the South Atlantic Ocean in the airspace managed by Atlantico (Brazil) and Dakar (Senegal) oceanic centers. Which country is responsible for the aircraft accident report?",
    "feedback": "France"
  },
  {
    "question": "Unless otherwise instructed by the appropriate air traffic service unit, an aircraft equipped with transponder, intercepted by another aircraft shall select immediately transponder Mode A",
    "feedback": "Code 7700"
  },
  {
    "question": "Except when a clearance is obtained from an ATC unit, a VFR flight shall not take off or land at an aerodrome within a CTR of Airspace Class C or D or enter the aerodrome traffic zone or traffic pattern when the ceiling is less than:",
    "feedback": "1 500 feet or visibility is less than 5 km"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where are taxiway centre line lights showing alternatively green and yellow installed?",
    "feedback": "From the beginning of a taxiway near the runway centre line to the perimeter of the ILS/MLS critical/sensitive area."
  },
  {
    "question": "The sole objective of the investigation of an accident or incident shall be the:",
    "feedback": "prevention of accidents or incidents"
  },
  {
    "question": "A detailed description of the visual ground aids can be found in ICAO:",
    "feedback": "Annex 14"
  },
  {
    "question": "A VFR flight constitutes essential traffic to other VFR flights, when operating in controlled airspace classified as:",
    "feedback": "B."
  },
  {
    "question": "For independent parallel approaches, the minimum radar separation provided until the aircraft is established inbound on the ILS localizer course and/or MLS final approach track is:",
    "feedback": "3.0 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the condition required so that an aerodrome may be considered as being controlled is:",
    "feedback": "The aerodrome shall be provided with a Control Tower"
  },
  {
    "question": "Transition from altitude to flight level, and vice-versa is done:",
    "feedback": "at transition altitude during climb and transition level during descent."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are on an IFR flight executing a circling approach. A descend below the MDA should not be made until :  1. the pilot has the landing threshold in sight 2. visual reference has been established and can be maintained  3. the required obstacle clearance can be maintained and a landing can be made  The combination regrouping all the correct answers is :",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3."
  },
  {
    "question": "The phases related for an aircraft to be in the state emergency or believed to be in emergency are",
    "feedback": "uncertainty, alert, distress"
  },
  {
    "question": "The required distance from clouds on a VFR flight above 3000 ft, outside controlled airspace, is:",
    "feedback": "1000 ft vertically and 1.5 km horizontally"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a radio altimeter operating area is:",
    "feedback": "to accommodate aeroplanes making auto-coupled approaches and automatic landings"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the relevant medical requirements, the applicant for a Commercial Pilot Licence shall hold a current:",
    "feedback": "class I medical assessment"
  },
  {
    "question": "For the boarding of potentially disruptive passengers supplementary safeguards are to be observe such as:",
    "feedback": "boarding the potentially disruptive passenger prior to all passengers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Except otherwise established by the appropriate ATS authority a Surveillance Radar Approach (SRA) shall be terminated at a distance from the touchdown of:",
    "feedback": "2 NM."
  },
  {
    "question": "The Convention defining rules of the parties relating to the carriage of passengers, baggage and cargo and the liability of the carriers and extent of compensation for damage is the:",
    "feedback": "Montreal Convention 1999"
  },
  {
    "question": "Non-precision approach runways and precision approach runways CAT I, II and III are defined as:",
    "feedback": "instrument runways"
  },
  {
    "question": "Runway centre line markings shall be provided on:",
    "feedback": "paved runways"
  },
  {
    "question": "For omnidirectional departures you can normally depart in any direction, but when there is a restriction it will be given in:",
    "feedback": "bearing and distance"
  },
  {
    "question": "Under which circumstances may a pilot deviate from a published instrument approach procedure?",
    "feedback": "If visual reference is established before the completion of the instrument approach procedure and the aircraft is cleared for a visual approach."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a precision approach (ILS), generally glide path interception occurs at heights above runway elevation between:",
    "feedback": "300m (984 ft) and 900m (2955 ft)."
  },
  {
    "question": "The conducting of an accident investigation may be delegated, in whole or in part, to:",
    "feedback": "Another State by mutual agreement and consent."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following defines 'flight visibility'?",
    "feedback": "The forward visibility from the flight deck of an aircraft in flight."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the appropriate IFR Flight Level for a magnetic track of 098° in RVSM airspace?",
    "feedback": "FL330"
  },
  {
    "question": "Normally all turns, which are requested by a radar controller have to be executed as:",
    "feedback": "Standard rate turns if not otherwise instructed by ATC."
  },
  {
    "question": "When the Mach number technique (MNT) is being applied, and the preceding aircraft shall maintain a mach number equal to or greater than the following aircraft a RNAV distance based  separation minimum may be used on the same direction tracks in lieu of 10 minutes longitudinal separation minimum. The distance is :",
    "feedback": "80 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "When ATC is equipped with and using Primary Surveillance Radar PSR, at what distance from the end of the runway may a pilot expect that his aircraft can be identified during a departure?",
    "feedback": "1NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "When an aircraft subjected to an unlawful interference has landed it shall notify by the most expeditius means of the State of registry of the aircraft and the State of the operator of the landing and shall similarly transmit all other relevant information to the:",
    "feedback": "Two aforementioned States, each State whose citizens suffered fatalities or injuries, each State whose citizens were detained as hostages, each State whose citizens are known to be on board the aircraft and the ICAO"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where does the final approach segment for a precision approach start?",
    "feedback": "FAP"
  },
  {
    "question": "When cargo, unaccompanied baggage or stores are not unladen at their intended destination but are unladen at another international airport, the contracting state where the unlading takes place; if satisfied that there has been no gross negligence or careless by the operator",
    "feedback": "shall not impose penalties, fines, customs duties and taxes on the operator"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the meanning of symbol 3 in the ground-air visual signal code?",
    "feedback": "operation completed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the Class of Airspace with the following conditions and services:\n\nIFR and VFR permitted\nAir Traffic Control Service: IFR flights\nSeparation: IFR from IFR\nTraffic information: for all flights as far as practicable",
    "feedback": "Airspace Class E"
  },
  {
    "question": "Segregated parallel approaches and departures (excluding semi-mixed parallel operations), are:",
    "feedback": "Simultaneous operations on parallel or near-parallel instrument runways in which one runway is used exclusively for approaches and the other runway is used exclusively for departures"
  },
  {
    "question": "Essential traffic information is provided to:",
    "feedback": "controlled traffic not separated from another controlled traffic with the prescribed separation minima"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which \"code letter\" shall be chosen to identify a taxiway to be used by an aircraft having a wheel base of 15 m?",
    "feedback": "Code letter \"C\"."
  },
  {
    "question": "According to ICAO Annex 2, all aircraft moving on the movement area of an aerodrome shall display navigation lights intended to indicate the relative path of the aircraft to an observer ......",
    "feedback": "from sunset to sunrise or during any other period prescribed by the appropriate authority"
  },
  {
    "question": "In airspace Class C below 3050 m/10000 ft AMSL the maximum speed for flights under VFR is",
    "feedback": "250 kt IAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "Above FL 290 the standard vertical flight separation between aircraft on the same direction is:",
    "feedback": "4000 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning to RNP (Required Navigation Performance) types, the indication RNP 4, represents a navigation accuracy of",
    "feedback": "plus or minus 4 NM on a 95 per cent containment basis"
  },
  {
    "question": "A braking action given by ATS of 0.25 and below is :",
    "feedback": "Poor"
  },
  {
    "question": "In accordance with the relevant Part-FCL requirements, as part of the total flight time requirement of 1500 hours for the issue of the ATPL, the minimum PIC flight time requirements are:",
    "feedback": "250 hours as PIC or\nnot less than 100 hours as PIC and the additional required flight time as co-pilot, performing under the supervision of the PIC the duties and functions of a PIC, provided that the method of supervision is acceptable to the licensing authority"
  },
  {
    "question": "The colour of a \"closed marking\" shall be:",
    "feedback": "White when displayed on a runway and yellow when displayed on a taxiway which is permanently closed to the use of aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a fixed-distance marking has to be provided this marking shall commence at :",
    "feedback": "300 m from threshold"
  },
  {
    "question": "When has a flight plan to be filed at the latest:",
    "feedback": "60 minutes before departure or, if filed in flight, 10 minutes before the aircraft is estimated to reach the intended point of entry into a control area or advisory area or the point of crossing an airway or advisory route."
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the Regulations and Acts associated with EASA. An Implementing Act is a....",
    "feedback": "binding Act adopted by the European Commission for the implementation of the Basic Regulation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following correctly lists special purpose codes that are to be used in conjunction with Secondary Surveillance Radar (SSR)?",
    "feedback": "Distress 7700.  Hijacking 7500. Communication failure 7600."
  },
  {
    "question": "The standard phrase used by an intercepting aircraft conveying the meaning \"descend for landing\" is:",
    "feedback": "DESCEND"
  },
  {
    "question": "Information signs other than location signs consist of:",
    "feedback": "black inscriptions on yellow background"
  },
  {
    "question": "When radar capabilities at a given location so permit, the minimum radar separation of 5 NM may be reduced, but shall not be less than:",
    "feedback": "3.0 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "When displayed in the signal area or at the end of the runway strip in use, a right-hand arrow of conspicuous colour indicates:",
    "feedback": "that in this runway direction turn before landing and after take off have to be made to the right"
  },
  {
    "question": "An applicant for a commercial pilot licence shall have completed in aeroplanes not less than:",
    "feedback": "10 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 5 hours may be instrument ground time"
  },
  {
    "question": "If contact is lost with the runway on the down-wind leg of a circling manoeuvre, what actions should be taken ?",
    "feedback": "Initiate a missed approach"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of altimeter setting is, that it will provide ......",
    "feedback": "vertical separation and adequate terrain clearance during all phases of flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "The aircraft commander, when he has reasonable grounds to believe that a person has commited or is about to commit an unlawful act on board the aircraft may:",
    "feedback": "deliver such person to the competent  authorities"
  },
  {
    "question": "Whenever ATIS is provided, the preparation and dissemination of the ATIS message shall be the responsability of",
    "feedback": "the air traffic services"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying from Italy to Libya. According to SERA, what rules must the aircraft follow when crossing the Mediterranean?",
    "feedback": "Annex 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Above 3050 m/10000 ft AMSL, the VMC minima for flights under VFR in all classes of airspace are:",
    "feedback": "visibility 8 km, distance from clouds 1500 m horizontal, 1000 ft vertical"
  },
  {
    "question": "The system notifying in advance the circumstances requiring important changes in the methods of operation, based on common effective dates, is identified by the acronym:",
    "feedback": "AIRAC"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a valid SSR mode A squawk?",
    "feedback": "A5678"
  },
  {
    "question": "Describe where the outbound timing begins in a holding pattern:",
    "feedback": "over or abeam the fix, whichever occurs later"
  },
  {
    "question": "For an IFR flight to an airport equipped with navaids, the estimated time of arrival is the estimated time at which the aircraft will:",
    "feedback": "arrive overhead the initial approach fix"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the relevant Part-FCL requirements, the minimum age for an applicant for a Commercial Pilot Licence shall not be less than:",
    "feedback": "18 years of age"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"A surveillance technique in which aircraft automatically provide, via data link, data derived from on-board navigation and position-fixing systems, including aircraft identification, four-dimensional position and additional data as appropriate\" is the definition for:",
    "feedback": "Automatic Dependent Surveillance (ADS)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Taxiway markings and aircraft stand markings are:",
    "feedback": "yellow"
  },
  {
    "question": "Above 14000 ft in still air, the outbound time on a 30° offset track is limited to:",
    "feedback": "1 minute 30 seconds"
  },
  {
    "question": "An airport provides two parallel runways where parallel approaches are conducted with departures interspersed on both runways. What type of operation is this?",
    "feedback": "Mixed operation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who establishes the OCA/H (Obstacle Clearance Altitude/Height) for an approach procedure?",
    "feedback": "the state"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Clearway\" is a defined rectangular area established to:",
    "feedback": "Permit aircraft to make a portion of its initial climb to a specific height."
  },
  {
    "question": "For aircraft flying over the high seas, which rules shall be in force?",
    "feedback": "The rules established under the Convention of international civil aviation."
  },
  {
    "question": "The outbound time in a holding pattern above 14000 ft in still air conditions is:",
    "feedback": "1 minute 30 seconds"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot receiving an IFR clearance from ATC should:",
    "feedback": "Read back the entire clearance as required by regulation."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is ICAO Annex 2 about?",
    "feedback": "Rules of the Air"
  },
  {
    "question": "The contents of Aeronautical Information Publication (AIP) are :",
    "feedback": "GEN, ENR (en-route) and AD (aerodromes)"
  },
  {
    "question": "A carrier is liable for damage sustained in the event of death  or wounding of a passenger if the accident that caused the damage:",
    "feedback": "Took place on board the aircraft or in the course of any of the operations of embarking and disembarking."
  },
  {
    "question": "Entering a holding pattern at FL 110 with a jet aircraft,  which will be the maximum speed ?",
    "feedback": "230 kt IAS."
  },
  {
    "question": "Independent parallel approaches to parallel runways:  The vectoring to intercept the ILS localizer course or MLS final approach track shall be such as to enable the aircraft to be established on the ILS localizer course or MLS final approach track in level flight, prior to intercept the ILS glide path or MLS elevation angle at a distance of at least",
    "feedback": "2.0 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The transition layer is the airspace located ....",
    "feedback": "between the Transition Level and the Transition Altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an approach procedure, a descent or climb conducted in a holding pattern is called:",
    "feedback": "Shuttle."
  },
  {
    "question": "Unless otherwise indicated, the missed approach procedures published on the IAC charts are based on a minimum climb gradient of",
    "feedback": "2.5%"
  },
  {
    "question": "When letters are used for the registration mark combinations shall not be used which might be confused with urgent or distress signals for example",
    "feedback": "XXX"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pattern \"B\" runway holding position marking at an intersection of a taxiway and a precision approach runway shall be supplemented ......",
    "feedback": "with a category I, II or III holding position sign as appropriate"
  },
  {
    "question": "Information on holding, approach and departure procedures can be found in part",
    "feedback": "ENR"
  },
  {
    "question": "An applicant for an Airline Transport Pilot Licence (ATPL) shall have completed in aeroplanes not less than:",
    "feedback": "75 hours of instrument time, of which not more than 30 hours may be instrument ground time"
  },
  {
    "question": "Taxiway edge lights shall be:",
    "feedback": "fixed showing blue"
  },
  {
    "question": "A series of green flashes from aerodrome control directed towards an aircraft in flight means:",
    "feedback": "return for landing"
  },
  {
    "question": "A \"RNAV\" distance based separation minimum may be used at the time the level is crossed, provided that each aircraft reports its distance to or from the same \"on track\" way-point. This minimum is:",
    "feedback": "80 NM."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which items of a received clearance must be read back to ATC?\n1) Altimeter settings2) Correct time3) Level, heading and speed instructions4) Runway in use5) SSR codes6) Taxi clearance7) Wind speed and direction",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4, 5, 6"
  },
  {
    "question": "Runway threshold identification lights are:",
    "feedback": "flashing white lights"
  },
  {
    "question": "For which aircraft is MCC required?",
    "feedback": "For multi-crew aeroplanes."
  },
  {
    "question": "An airport security programme shall be established by each State for:",
    "feedback": "Each airport serving international civil aviation."
  },
  {
    "question": "The correct EASA Part-FCL definition for multi pilot aircraft with regard to aeroplanes is:",
    "feedback": "Aeroplanes certificated for operation with a minimum crew of at least two pilots"
  },
  {
    "question": "Air Traffic Control Services have the responsibility to prevent terrain collisions:",
    "feedback": "when a flight under IFR is vectored by radar"
  },
  {
    "question": "Using the ground - air visual signal code, the letter similar to the symbol meaning \"REQUIRE ASSISTANCE\" is :",
    "feedback": "5"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the principle requirement for a signals area on an aerodrome?",
    "feedback": "It must be clearly visible from the air."
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is responsible for determining the continuing airworthiness of an aeroplane?",
    "feedback": "the state of registry"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the following definition for GM to FCL.010B?\nDefinition: The administrative action taken after a rating or approval has lapsed that renews the privileges of the rating or approval for a further specified period consequent upon the fulfilment of specified requirements.",
    "feedback": "Renewal"
  },
  {
    "question": "The MSA, which must be established around a navigation facility, is in general valid within a sector of :",
    "feedback": "25 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Required Navigation Performance (RNP) shall be prescribed",
    "feedback": "by states on the basis of regional air navigation agreements"
  },
  {
    "question": "Longitudinal separation minima based on distance using DME for aircraft at the same cruising level and track, provided that each aircraft utilizes \"on Track\" DME stations and separation is checked by obtaining simultaneous DME readings, is :",
    "feedback": "20 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where an upper flight information region (UIR) is established, the procedures applicable therein",
    "feedback": "do not have to be identical with those established for the flight information region below"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not found on the Certificate of Registration?",
    "feedback": "the category of aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Under what circumstances would an ILS glide path in excess of 3° be used?",
    "feedback": "Where other means of obstacle clearance are impracticable."
  },
  {
    "question": "What action should be taken if contact is lost with the aerodrome on the down wind leg ?",
    "feedback": "Initiate a missed approach"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft, registered in Italy, is flying over the Mediterranean. At the moment, it is 100 NM from the nearest coast, inside Libyan FIR. From the following options, choose the ones that need to be checked to verify that the correct Rules of the Air are complied with:\n1) SERA2) Italian rules3) Libyan rules4) High Seas rules5) ICAO Annex 2",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The speed limitation for both IFR flights and VFR flights inside ATS airspace classified as B, when flying below 3.050 m (10.000 ft) AMLS, is :",
    "feedback": "Not applicable"
  },
  {
    "question": "Your transponder code assigned by ATC is 5320.\nIn flight, in case of radio communications failure, you will squawk code :",
    "feedback": "A 7600 Mode C"
  },
  {
    "question": "The sign depicted is a:",
    "feedback": "Stand identification sign"
  },
  {
    "question": "The shortest distance in the landing sequence between a 'HEAVY' and a preceding 'LIGHT' aircraft is:",
    "feedback": "3 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The First Freedom of the air defined in the International Air Services Transit Agreement is the:",
    "feedback": "right to overfly another State without landing"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following events are mandatory to be reported according to EU regulation No. 376/2014?",
    "feedback": "Captain incapacitation due to intoxication from the crew meal"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot receives an EAT as soon as practicable, when the expected approach delay is:",
    "feedback": "10 minutes or more"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the meaning if ground-air visual signal 9?",
    "feedback": "Have divided into two groups, and each group is proceeding in the direction indicated"
  },
  {
    "question": "Any aircraft deriving its lift in flight chiefly from aerodynamic forces is:",
    "feedback": "A heavier-than-air aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following objectives is not an objective of air traffic services?",
    "feedback": "Provide advice and information for the safe and efficient preparation of flights."
  },
  {
    "question": "According to ICAO DOC 8168 PANS-OPS, flight level zero shall be located at the atmospheric pressure level of 1013.25 hPa. Consecutive flight levels shall be separated by a pressure interval corresponding to at least ...... in the standard atmosphere.",
    "feedback": "500 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "The privilege to land for non-traffic purposes, e.g. refuelling, maintenance is to following freedom of the air:",
    "feedback": "2nd freedom."
  },
  {
    "question": "If radio contact with the intercepting aircraft is established but communication on a common language is not possible, the pilot of the intercepted aircraft shall communicate to the intercepting aircraft that he is unable to comply with the instructions by pronouncing the phrase",
    "feedback": "CAN NOT"
  },
  {
    "question": "Acceleration Stop Distance Available/ASDA is the length of the:",
    "feedback": "take-off run available plus the length of stopway (if stopway provided) ."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following lights is a high intensity obstacle light:",
    "feedback": "Flashing white light."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following group shows the correct designators for three parallel runways seen from the direction of the approach?",
    "feedback": "29L, 29C, 29R"
  },
  {
    "question": "An ATS airspace where IFR and VFR flights are permitted, all participating IFR flights receive an air traffic advisory service and all flights receive flight information service if requested, is classified",
    "feedback": "Airspace F"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the role and objective of EASA?",
    "feedback": "EASA proposes implementing rules to the European Commission and promotes the highest common standards of safety and environmental protection in civil aviation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where State has not established minimum IFR altitudes, the minimum height of an aircraft above the highest obstacle over high terrain, or in mountainous areas shall be for an IFR flight :",
    "feedback": "at least 2000 feet within 8 KM of the estimated position"
  },
  {
    "question": "The minimum separation to be applied between a LIGHT or MEDIUM aircraft, taking off behind a HEAVY aircraft using the same runway is:",
    "feedback": "2 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Approach Control Service is an air traffic control service",
    "feedback": "An air traffic control service provided for the arriving and departing controlled flights."
  },
  {
    "question": "Independent parallel approaches may be conducted to parallel runways provided that a no transgression zone (NTZ) of at least :",
    "feedback": "610 m is established between extended runway centre lines and as is depicted on the radar display"
  },
  {
    "question": "If visual reference is lost while circling to land from an instrument approach, it is expected that the pilot will make an initial climbing turn towards the:",
    "feedback": "Landing runway."
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the Class of Airspace with the following conditions and services:\n\nIFR and VFR permitted\nAir Traffic Control Service: all flights\nSeparation: IFR from IFR\nTraffic information: IFR receive traffic information in respect of VFR flights, VFR receive traffic information in respect of all other flights",
    "feedback": "Airspace Class D"
  },
  {
    "question": "Unless otherwise prescribed, what is the rule regarding the level to be maintained by an aircraft flying IFR outside controlled airspace?",
    "feedback": "1 000 feet above the highest obstacle within 8 kilometres of the estimated position of the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a flight from Prague to Vienna, an in-flight loss of control occurred. The European Regulation on Air Operations contains rules on reporting such occurences. This Regulation has been....",
    "feedback": "drafted by EASA for the European Commission"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is charged with the safe conduct of a flight?",
    "feedback": "The pilot in command"
  },
  {
    "question": "An operator shall not operate an aeroplane certificated to CS 25, across an area in which search and rescue would be especially difficult, without survival equipment if it flies away from an area suitable for making an emergency landing at a distance greater than :",
    "feedback": "90 minutes at cruising speed."
  },
  {
    "question": "When the holders of aircraft transport pilot licences aeroplane and helicopter, engaged in single-pilot commercial operations, have passed their 40th birthday the medical examination shall be reduced from:",
    "feedback": "12 months to 6 months"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a stepdown fix is established on the final approach track, a descend shall be made so as to :",
    "feedback": "pass the fix not below the specified crossing altitude."
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight that has the highest priority for landing is",
    "feedback": "an aircraft that is compelled to land (emergency landing)"
  },
  {
    "question": "As part of the total flight time requirement of 1500 hours for the issue of the ATPL in accordance with the relevant Part-FCL requirements, an applicant shall have completed not less than 200 hours of cross-country flight time.\n\nHow many of these hours shall be PIC time or co-pilot time performing the duties and functions of a PIC under the supervision of a PIC, provided that the method of supervision is acceptable to the licensing authority?",
    "feedback": "at least 100 hours PIC flight time and not less than 100 hours supervised co-pilot flight time"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the relevant Part-FCL requirements, the applicant for a commercial pilot licence aeroplane shall have completed in aeroplanes not less than:",
    "feedback": "200 hours of flight time or 150 hours if completed during a course of approved training as a pilot of aeroplanes"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft approaching the holding pattern makes a left turn onto heading 90° for 1 minute. Then it turns left for capturing the inbound magnetic track of 270°. Select the appropriate entry procedure:",
    "feedback": "Parallel entry procedure"
  },
  {
    "question": "The tolerance value used to determine that mode C derived level information displayed to the controller is accurate shall be:",
    "feedback": "+/- 300 ft."
  },
  {
    "question": "If a communication failure is experienced on an IFR flight in IMC, the pilot shall:",
    "feedback": "proceed to the navigation aid serving the destination aerodrome and commence descent at the expected approach time or, if no expected approach time has been received, as close as possible to the estimated time of arrival resulting from the current flight plan."
  },
  {
    "question": "The procedure describing the visual phase following an instrument approach, brining an aircraft into position for the landing on a runway different from the one for straight-in approach, is called:",
    "feedback": "Visual manoeuvring (circling)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"PAPI\" shall consist of:",
    "feedback": "A wing bar of 4 sharp transition multi-lamp or paired units equally spaced."
  },
  {
    "question": "To expedite the approach, an aircraft may be asked to:",
    "feedback": "pass a specified point inbound at the previously notified time"
  },
  {
    "question": "The minimum obstacle clearance requirement at the end of the primary area of the intermediate approach segment in an instrument approach procedure is:",
    "feedback": "150m (492 ft)"
  },
  {
    "question": "To which of the following areas does ICAO Annex 13 (Aircraft Accident and Incident Investigation) apply?",
    "feedback": "To any geographical area."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the appropriate IFR Flight Level for a magnetic track of 125° in non-RVSM airspace?",
    "feedback": "FL290"
  },
  {
    "question": "A minimum vertical separation shall be provided until aircraft are established inbound on the ILS localizer course and/or MLS final approach track. This minimum is, when independent parallel approaches are being conducted :",
    "feedback": "300 m (1000 ft)"
  },
  {
    "question": "When an aircraft is vectored by radar to the localiser course, the angle between the interception course and the localiser course is normally 30 degrees. In accordance with DOC 4444 this angle shall not be greater than:",
    "feedback": "45 degrees"
  },
  {
    "question": "The registration mark shall be assigned by",
    "feedback": "State of Registry or a common mark registering Authority"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pilot in command of an aircraft:\n\n1 - must comply immediately to all instructions received from ATC.\n2 - is responsible only if he is the \"pilot flying\".\n3 - may deviate from air regulations for safety reasons.\n4 - may be exempt from air regulations in order to comply to an ATC instruction.\n5 - may ask for the modification of an unsatisfactory clearance.\n\nWhich of the following combinations contains all of the correct statements?",
    "feedback": "3 - 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The objectives of ICAO were established and are ratified by the:",
    "feedback": "Chicago convention 1944"
  },
  {
    "question": "If an aircraft is missing:",
    "feedback": "it is classified as an accident."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a precision approach (ILS), the final approach segment begins at the:",
    "feedback": "FAP."
  },
  {
    "question": "When the aircraft carries serviceable Mode C transponder, the pilot shall continuously operate this mode:",
    "feedback": "unless otherwise directed by ATC"
  },
  {
    "question": "The State conducting an accident investigation shall:",
    "feedback": "Publish a final report according to ICAO Standards."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the event that a controlled flight inadvertently deviates from its current flight plan, the appropriate ATC unit has to be informed:",
    "feedback": "when the average TAS at cruising level between reporting points varies or is expected to vary by plus or minus 5 percent from the TAS given in the flight plan"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the case of parallel runways, each runway designation number shall be supplemented:",
    "feedback": "By a letter - for example 2 parallel runways \"L\" and \"R\" - for 3 \"L\", \"C\" and \"R\"."
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of airspace is normally established at the confluence of ATS routes in the vicinity of one or more major aerodromes?",
    "feedback": "Terminal Control Area (TMA)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Each contracting state shall provide an Aeronautical Information Service (AIS) in its territory and for areas in which the state is responsible for the Air Traffic Services outside its territory, and this shall include the preparation and origination of:",
    "feedback": "Integrated Aeronautical Information Package."
  },
  {
    "question": "Two aircraft are departing from a reporting point defined by an NDB. What is the minimum track separation required before one aircraft would be permitted to climb/descend through the other aircraft's level?",
    "feedback": "30° and a distance of 15 nm or more."
  },
  {
    "question": "The Transition Level",
    "feedback": "is normally an integrated part of the ATIS"
  },
  {
    "question": "You are on VOR track 332° for a straight-in approach. What runway direction could be expected?",
    "feedback": "302° - 002°"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is being subjected to unlawful interference ('hijacked') in non RVSM airspace. The pilot is forced to divert from the cleared track and/or cruising level without being able to communicate this to ATS. He shall try to:",
    "feedback": "proceed at a level which differs from the cruising level normally used for IFR flights in that area by 1000 ft above FL 290 or 500 ft below FL 290"
  },
  {
    "question": "As a rule, while establishing the departure procedures, the operator reckons that an aeroplane has a climb gradient of:",
    "feedback": "3.3% with all engines operating."
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is responsible for the development of the contingency procedures required to cover the case of engine failure during an instrument departure, which occurs after V1?",
    "feedback": "The operator of the aircraft."
  },
  {
    "question": "A \"barrette\" consists of:",
    "feedback": "three or more groundlights closely spaced together to appear as a bar of lights"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is meant by the term \"Special VFR\"?",
    "feedback": "A VFR flight cleared by ATC to operate within a CTR in meteorological conditions below VMC"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot is flying IFR in the upper airspace, classified as Class C. What type of air traffic service will the pilot receive?",
    "feedback": "Air traffic control"
  },
  {
    "question": "A precision approach runway CAT II is an instrument runway served by ILS and visual aids intended for operations down to:",
    "feedback": "a RVR of not less than 350 meters and a DH of not less than 100 ft."
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the relevant Part-FCL requirements, an applicant for a commercial pilot licence aeroplane shall have completed in aeroplanes not less than:",
    "feedback": "20 hours of cross country flight time as pilot-in-command including a cross country flight not less than 540 km (300NM)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Containers or packages containing survival equipment for dropping should have the general nature of the content indicated by a colour code.\n\nThe colour of droppable containers and streamers for medical supply and first aid equipment is:",
    "feedback": "Red"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Certificate of Airworthiness shall be issued on the basis of satisfactory evidence that the aircraft complies with the design aspects of the appropriate airworthiness requirements. Who issues the Certificate of Airworthiness?",
    "feedback": "The State of Registry"
  },
  {
    "question": "Member states should introduce specific security measures for the air transport of the following groups of potentially disruptive passengers defined below :",
    "feedback": "Deportees, inadmissible persons and persons in lawful custody"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following Annexes to the Chicago convention contains minimum specifications for a crew licence to have international validity?",
    "feedback": "Annex 1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Flight information service provided to flights shall include the provision of information concerning collision hazards to aircraft operating in airspace classes:",
    "feedback": "C to G (inclusive)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Approach Control has the following duties:",
    "feedback": "Inform aircraft if the approach delay is greater than 30 minutes."
  },
  {
    "question": "Commission Regulation (EU) No 965/2012 applies:",
    "feedback": "to all types of commercial and non-commercial operations"
  },
  {
    "question": "When on a RNP 1 route is indicated A342 Z, means that all turns shall be made within the allowable RNP tolerance of a tangential arc between the straight leg segments with a radius of :",
    "feedback": "15 NM on the route between 30° and 90° at and below FL 190"
  },
  {
    "question": "The validity of Type Ratings and multi-engine Class Ratings is one year from the date:",
    "feedback": "Of issue"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following has the right-of-way against a vehicle that is operating on an apron?",
    "feedback": "An aircraft being towed"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"TODA\" is the length of the:",
    "feedback": "take-off run available plus the length of clearway available (if provided)."
  },
  {
    "question": "The ground-air visual signal code for use by survivors on ground to indicate \"AFFIRMATIVE\" is:",
    "feedback": "Y"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft shall display, if so equipped, an anti-collision light:",
    "feedback": "on the ground when the engines are running"
  },
  {
    "question": "A passenger has lost his/her ticket, which was issued by an airline. In this case....",
    "feedback": "the contract of carriage is not affected"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"3-BAR AVASIS\", \"PAPI\" and \"T-VASIS\" shall be provided for aircraft having eye-to-wheel heights, when in the flare attitude, not exceeding:",
    "feedback": "Approximately 16 m."
  },
  {
    "question": "The International Civil Aviation Convention Annex containing standards and recommended practices for Personnel Licensing is :",
    "feedback": "Annex 1"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Transition Level",
    "feedback": "shall be the lowest flight level available for use above the transition altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Part SERA, aircraft bearing the nationality and registration marks of a Member State of the EU, when flying over the high seas, are required to follow the Rules of the Air specified....",
    "feedback": "in Annex 2 of the Chicago Convention"
  },
  {
    "question": "A radio communications, \"Distress\" differs from \"Urgency\" because in the first case:",
    "feedback": "There is a serious and imminent danger requiring immediate assistance."
  },
  {
    "question": "An applicant for an Airline Transport Pilot Licence aeroplane (ATPL(A)) shall have completed in aeroplanes not less than ... hours, either as pilot-in-command or made up by not less than ... hours as pilot-in-command and the additional flight time as co-pilot performing under the supervision of the pilot-in-command the duties and functions of a pilot-in-command provided that the method of supervision is acceptable to the licensing authority. The above state hours are respectively:",
    "feedback": "250;70"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a VFR flight, your magnetic track is 005°, the magnetic heading 355°. Which of the following flight level is correct?",
    "feedback": "FL 55"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is competent to issue a Certificate of Airworthiness?",
    "feedback": "The Contracting State which approves the aircraft on the basis of satisfactory evidence that the aircraft complies with appropriated airworthiness requirements."
  },
  {
    "question": "The longitudinal separation minima based on time between aircraft at same cruising level where navigation aids permit frequent determination of position and speed, is:",
    "feedback": "10 minutes."
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the ATS Route Designator UM-120-RNP signify?",
    "feedback": "Upper (airspace), regional ATS route network, RNAV"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to ICAO DOC 7300/9 Convention on International Civil Aviation, article to \"Landing at customs airport\", which statement is correct?",
    "feedback": "Aircraft are permitted to cross the territory of a Contracting State without landing, unless the regulations of that State requires a landing for customs examination"
  },
  {
    "question": "Using the ground - air visual code the symbol meaning \"we have found all personnel\" is :",
    "feedback": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "The outbound time in a holding pattern at 14000 ft or below in still air conditions is:",
    "feedback": "1 minute"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is responsible for the initiation of an accident investigation?",
    "feedback": "the Authority of the State in which the accident occurred"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Commission Implementing Regulation (EU) No 2017/373 provides, amongst others:\n1) General requirements for the provision of air navigation services2) General requirements for the provision of air traffic services3) Specific requirements for the provision of meteorological services4) Specific requirements for the provision of aeronautical information services \nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The assigment of the common mark to a common mark registering authority will be made by :",
    "feedback": "the International Civil Aviation Organisation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an air traffic controller, using radar to provide ATC, required to do prior to providing an aircraft with ATC based on radar information?",
    "feedback": "Radar identify the aircraft and inform the pilot."
  },
  {
    "question": "The holder of a pilot licence, when acting as co-pilot of an aircraft required to be operated with a co-pilot, shall be entitled to be credit with not more than :",
    "feedback": "50 % of the co-pilot flight time towards the total flight time required for a higher grade of pilot licence"
  },
  {
    "question": "When an aircraft carries a serviceable transponder, the pilot shall operate the transponder:",
    "feedback": "At all times during flight, regardless of whether the aircraft is within or outside airspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to ICAO Annex 12, \"emergency phase\" means ....",
    "feedback": "Uncertainty phase, alert phase, or distress phase"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where a final approach fix (FAF) is specified for a non-precision approach procedure, what is the minimum obstacle clearance fixed margin that is applied for all aircraft?",
    "feedback": "75 m (246 ft)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Annex 7 (Aircraft Nationality and Registration Marks) contains:",
    "feedback": "standards only"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a holding pattern all turns are to be made at a :",
    "feedback": "rate of 3°per second or at a bank angle of 25°, which ever requires the lesser bank."
  }
]